<?xml version="1.0"?>  <database>	<character origin="mutant" date="1986" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Bronze" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Apocalypse</name>      <identity>En Sabah Nur</identity>      <creator>Louise Simonson and Jackson Guice</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Immortality, energy blasts, teleportation, superhuman strength, speed and stamina, shape-shifting and size-shifting, force field generation, telepathy, psychokinesis.</powers>      <weakness>Can be killed while transferring consciousness.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Apocalypse is a fictional comic book supervillain in the Marvel Comics' universe. He is a virtually immortal mutant bonded with extra-terrestrial technology.<br /><br />A powerful foe of the X-Men, Apocalypse is often accompanied by four servants, the Four Horsemen of Apocalypse, named after the Four Hoursemen of the Book of Revelation.<br /><br />Apocalypse has empowered a number of servants besides his horsemen. These include Ozymandias, Exodus, Sinister, the Harbinger of Apocalypse and Moses Magnum. He is also served for a time by a treacherous team of Inhumans and mutants known as the Dark Riders. The Dark Riders later declare their loyalty to Stryfe. Apocalypse is also worshipped by a number of cults and individuals, such as the feline mutant Anais, who still roam the world.<br /><br />Aside from his superhuman powers, Apocalypse is also extraordinarily intelligent, a genius with knowledge of science and technology centuries ahead of conventional science. This was not merely a result of his exposure to alien technology, as he was able to make significant new advances beyond the alien materials to which he was exposed.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Apocalypse">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/marvel/Apocalypse.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apocalypse_%28comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Gambit|Incredible Hulk|Phoenix|Psylocke|Wolverine</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1941" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Missing">		<name>Aquaman</name>      <identity>Orin</identity>      <creator>Paul Norris and Mort Weisinger</creator>      <company>More Fun Comics (now DC Comics)</company>      <powers>Undersea adaptation, telepathy with marine life, enhanced physical attributes, enchanted left hand.</powers>      <weakness>Cannot be out of water for more than an hour, workaholic, depression.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Aquaman is a DC Comics superhero. Created by Paul Norris and Mort Weisinger, he first appeared in <em>More Fun Comics #73</em> (1941).<br /><br />Like Marvel Comics' <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Namor">Namor</a>, the Sub-Mariner, Aquaman is an undersea hero originating from the mythical kingdom of Atlantis. In the traditional version of his origin, he was Arthur Curry, the son of Tom Curry, a human lighthouse keeper, and Atlanna, an outcast from Atlantis. Recent comics, however, depict Aquaman as an orphan of purely underwater heritage who was briefly raised by a lighthouse keeper named Arthur Curry. In either case, Arthur eventually learned about his origins and powers, and vowed to defend the Earth's oceans and their aquatic inhabitants.<br /><br />Aquaman, born as Orin to Atlantean Queen Atlanna and the mysterious wizard Atlan, was abandoned on Mercy Reef as a baby because of his blonde hair, which was seen by the superstitious denizens of Atlantis as a sign of a curse they called "the Mark of Kordax." The only one who spoke up on Orin's behalf was Vulko, a scientist who had no patience for myth or superstition, and while his pleas were to no avail, Vulko would later become a close friend and advisor to the young Orin.<br /><br />As a child, Orin was found and taken in by a lighthouse keeper who gave him his human name, Arthur Curry. One day Orin returned home and found his adoptive father had disappeared, so he set off on his own. In his early teens, Orin ventured to the far north, where he met and fell in love with an Inupiat girl named Kako. He also first earned the hatred of Orm, the future Ocean Master, who would later be revealed to be Arthur's half-brother. He was driven away before he could learn that Kako had become pregnant with his son, Koryak.<br /><br />In 1960, Aquaman was included in the Justice League of America comic, appearing with the team in their very first adventure in and was later revealed to be a founding member. Aquaman took part in most of the 1960s adventures of the superhero team. The 1960s also saw the introduction of enemies such as <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Ocean Master">Ocean Master</a> and Black Manta, would-be conquerors of the sea.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/secret_files/pdfs/aquaman.pdf">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/dc/Aquaman.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aquaman">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Batman|Black Canary|Flash|Green Arrow|Green Lantern|Hawkman|Martian Manhunter|Plastic Man|Superman|Wonder Woman</allies>		<enemies>Ocean Master</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="altered" date="1993" gender="male" morality="nblurred" era="Bronze" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Bane</name>      <identity>Unknown</identity>      <creator>Chuck Dixon, Graham Nolan, and Doug Moench</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>Superhuman strength and stamina, enhanced speed.</powers>      <weakness>Dependance on Vemon although it causes mental and physical damage.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Bane is the DC Comics villain best known for breaking <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Batman">Batman</a>'s back.<br /><br />Bane possesses superhuman or near-superhuman strength (strength level varies somewhat depending on the source), enhanced by his use of the drug "Venom." He is also quite intelligent (having deduced Batman's secret identity) and devious (he crafted the escape from Arkham Asylum of all of Batman's enemies).<br /><br />Born to serve the life sentence of his father, Bane's childhood and early adult life were spent behind the walls of Pena Duro, an infamous prison located in Santa Prisca. The writers created Bane as dark mirror of Batman's both in origin and in his gifts.<br /><br />Though imprisoned, his natural abilities allowed him to gain extraordinary skills within the walls of Santa Prisca. He read as many books as he could get his hands on, built up his body in the prison's gymnasium, and learned to fight in the merciless school of prison life. Despite his circumstances, he appears to have found teachers of various sorts during his incarceration, ranging from the hardened convicts who were his company from birth to an elderly Jesuit priest under whose tutelage he apparently received a classical education. Bane would murder this priest upon his return to Santa Prisca years later. However, he committed the first of his murders at the age of eight. As an adult, he became a test subject for a mysterious drug known as Venom, which had killed its other subjects. It nearly killed him at first, but he survived and found its effects enhanced his physical strength, although he needed to take it every twelve hours via a system of cables pumped directly into his body or he suffered debilitating side-effects.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/dc/Bane.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bane_%28comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Batman|Nightwing|Ra's al Ghul</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1939" gender="male" morality="antihero" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Batman</name>      <identity>Bruce Wayne</identity>      <creator>Bob Kane and Bill Finger</creator>      <company>National Publications (now DC Comics)</company>      <powers>No superhuman powers. Peak human physical condition, genius-level intellect, master of martial arts, acrobatics, strength, escape artistry, and detective skills.</powers>      <weakness>Emotionally distant, paranoia, arrogance.</weakness>	  <copy><p>In early 1939, the success of <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Superman">Superman</a> in Action Comics prompted editors at the comic book division of National Publications to request more superheroes for their titles. In response, Bob Kane created a character called "the Bat-Man". Finger wrote the first Batman story and Kane provided the art. The Batman was a breakout hit, with sales on Detective Comics soaring to the point that National's comic book division was renamed "Detective Comics, Inc." (later DC Comics).<br /><br />His true identity is Bruce Wayne, billionaire industrialist, playboy, and philanthropist who was driven to fight crime in Gotham City. Witnessing the murder of his parents as a child led him to train himself to the peak of physical and intellectual perfection, don a costume, and fight crime. One of the highlights of Batman's character is that unlike many other superheroes, he does not possess superhuman powers or abilities; he makes use of intellect, detective skills, technology, and physical prowess in his war on crime.<br /><br />Batman is supported by Superman and members of the Justice League of America and the Outsiders, both of which he is usually a part-time member. Superman especially crosses paths with Batman often, given that the two are DC Comics' most prominent characters.<br /><br />The <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Joker">Joker</a> has been featured as the arch nemesis of the Caped Crusader throughout the Batman saga. Other well known villains include <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Catwoman">Catwoman</a>, the <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Penguin">Penguin</a>, Two-Face, the Riddler, Mad Hatter, Scarecrow, Man-Bat and Clayface.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/secret_files/pdfs/batman.pdf">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/dc/BatmanI.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Batman">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Black Canary|Flash|Green Arrow|Green Lantern|Hawkman|Martian Manhunter|Nightwing|Oracle|Plastic Man|Superman|Wonder Woman</allies>		<enemies>Bane|Catwoman|Joker|Lex Luthor|Penguin|Ra's al Ghul</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="altered" date="1947" gender="female" morality="hero" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Black Canary</name>      <identity>Dinah Drake Lance</identity>      <creator>Robert Kanigher and Carmine Infantino</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>Expert in hand-to-hand combat, "Canary Cry" - an ultrasonic scream.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The Black Canary was originally a non-superpowered crimefighter who relied on martial arts and detective skills to combat crime. Later the character was given a superhuman sonic scream dubbed the "Canary Cry" that could be used to shatter objects or disable opponents. She has often been referred to as "The Blonde Bombshell" due to her extraordinary beauty and sex appeal (although for many years, her blonde hair was actually a wig), which have been accentuated by her trademark fishnet stockings (which she has worn off and on since her inception).<br /><br />In her secret identity, Dinah Drake was a black-haired florist whose romantic interest was Larry Lance. Her costume covered her hair with a blonde wig besides her trademark mesh stockings (it could be suggested that what she wore was not really fishnets but rather blue leggings with a black fishnet pattern), pirate boots, bathing-suit like garment, and her jacket, which is never buttoned. Initially, she also wore a variant of a domino mask. Black Canary soon joined the Justice Society of America as a heroine, not as a mole, and ceased being published along with the rest of the team by the early 1950s.<br /><br />Shortly into the League's history she met <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Green Arrow">Green Arrow</a>. While Dinah couldn't stand him at first, they later became involved despite an obvious age difference. Dinah remained part of the League for roughly six years before it was dissolved. It was during that time her mother died as a result of radiation poisoning, a result of a battle years earlier with the villain Aquarius. This affected her deeply and led to her accepting her time in the JLA was over.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/dc/BlackCanaryII.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Canary">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Batman|Catwoman</allies>		<enemies>Joker|Nightwing|Ra's al Ghul</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="hybrid" date="1973" gender="male" morality="antihero" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Blade</name>      <identity>Eric Brooks</identity>      <creator>Gene Colan and Marv Wolfman</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Regenerative healing factor, vampiric strength, undead speed, unique ability to "smell" supernatural creatures, unique martial-artist.</powers>      <weakness>Bright light, vampire cravings.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The character Blade was created in 1973 for Marvel Comics by writer Marv Wolfman and artist Gene Colan and was a supporting character in the 1970s comic <em>Tomb of Dracula</em>.<br /><br />The man called Blade was born into the darker side of reality in a whorehouse, likely somewhere in Great Britain.<br /><br />Blade's mother, a prostitute at Madame Vanity's brothel, experienced severe labor complications, and a doctor was summoned. The name of the "doctor" was Deacon Frost, in reality a bloodthirsty vampire. Frost feasted on Blade's mother during his birth, killing her, and accidentally passed along certain enzymes in his own blood to the infant, which later resulted in Blade's immunity to being turned; his ability to "smell" supernatural creatures; a greatly prolonged lifespan; and sensitivity to bright light.<br /><br />Blade has all the strengths of a vampire, but none of their weaknesses. He has at times referred to himself as a dhampir, though this is not strictly true. He does, however, greatly resemble the creatures he hunts.<br /><br />Blade can see in the dark, is a great deal stronger than a normal human being, has faster reflexes, a regenerative healing factor, he can "smell" supernatural creatures of all kinds, and he is immune to being turned into a full vampire via a vampire's bite.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Blade">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/Blade.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blade_%28comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies></enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="mutant" date="1958" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Silver" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Brainiac</name>      <identity>Vril Dox</identity>      <creator>Otto Binder</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>A vast, superior intelligence limited only by the technology it currently inhabits.</powers>      <weakness>Hubris, emotional conflict.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Brainiac is a fictional supervillain in the DC Comics universe, most often appearing as an opponent of Superman.<br /><br />First appearing in <em>Action Comics #242</em> (July 1958), Brainiac was a bald, green-skinned humanoid who arrived on Earth and shrank various cities including Metropolis, storing them in bottles with the intent of using them to restore Bryak, the planet he ruled. He was accompanied by a "space monkey" named Koko.<br /><br />A ruthless extraterrestrial villain - in reality an ingenious humanoid computer created by the sinister computer tyrants of a far-distant planet - who has been an implacable foe of <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Superman">Superman</a> since July, 1958.<br /><br />An evil space mastermind and fearsome super-foe with an arsenal of awesome nightmarish scientific weapons at his command, and is perhaps the most terrible evil-doer in all the universe, a creature of superhuman intelligence, great scientific ability, and utter ruthlessness who is said to know the universe as no mere man knows it.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brainiac_%28comics%29">Wikipedia</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/dc/Brainiac13.htm">Spider-Bob's</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Lex Luthor|Superman</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1976" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Bullseye</name>      <identity>Lester</identity>      <creator>Marv Wolfman and George Perez</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Unerring and deadly aim with any object he can throw, shoot, or spit; adamantium spinal column.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Bullseye is a fictional character, a supervillain in the Marvel Comics universe who is primarily an enemy of <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Daredevil">Daredevil</a>. He was created by Marv Wolfman and Bob Brown in <i>Daredevil</i> Vol. 1, #131 (March 1976).<br /><br />Bullseye is a psychopathic assassin with the ability to use any object, such as a playing card, a shuriken, or even a pencil, and throw or shoot it with lethal accuracy. However, he finds Daredevil a frustrating target since the superhero's senses allow him sufficient time and information to determine where Bullseye is aiming his attacks and when he is going to launch them, thus allowing him to evade or block the attack most of the time.<br /><br />Bullseye's real name and origins are unknown. He has used the alias Benjamin Poindexter on several occasions; in the Ultimate Marvel Universe, this is his real name. <em>Daredevil Vol. 2, #49</em> (Sept. 2003) revealed Bullseye's first name to be Lester. The miniseries <em>Bullseye: Greatest Hits</em> (2004) developed the character's backstory, but also revealed that some or all of it has been fabricated by Bullseye himself.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Bullseye">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.spider-bob.com/villains/marvel/BullseyeI.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bullseye_(comics)">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Kingpin</allies>		<enemies>Daredevil</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="altered" date="1941" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Golden" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Captain America</name>      <identity>Steve Rogers</identity>      <creator>Joe Simon and Jack Kirby</creator>      <company>Timely Comics (now Marvel Comics)</company>      <powers>An artificially enhanced physiology at the maximum human level of strength, endurance and agility, indestructible shield which he can throw with unerring accuracy.</powers>      <weakness>No blatant weaknesses.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Captain America, the alter ego of Steve Rogers (in some accounts Steven Grant Rogers), is a fictional superhero in the Marvel Comics universe. Created by Joe Simon and Jack Kirby, he first appeared in Timely Comics' <em>Captain America Comics #1</em> (March 1941).<br /><br />Steven Rogers was a scrawny American fine arts student specializing in illustration in the early 1940s before America's entry into World War II. He was disturbed by the rise of the Third Reich enough to attempt to enlist only to be rejected due to his poor constitution. By chance, a US Army officer looking for test subjects for a top secret defense research project offered Rogers an alternate way to serve his country. This project, Operation: Rebirth, consisted of developing a means to create physically superior soldiers and Rogers was deemed ideal.<br /><br />Rogers agreed to volunteer for the research and after a rigorous physical and combat training and selection process, was chosen as the first human test subject for a chemical formula that was termed the Super-Soldier Serum, developed by the scientist Dr. Emil Erskine (who was code-named "Dr. Reinstein").<br /><br />The night that Operation: Rebirth was implemented, Rogers received injections and oral ingestions of the Super-Soldier formula. He was then exposed to a controlled burst of "Vita-Rays" that activated and stabilized the chemicals in his system. Although the process was arduous physically, it successfully altered his physiology almost instantly from its relatively frail form to the maximum of human efficiency, greatly enhancing his musculature and reflexes. Erskine declared Rogers to be the first of a new breed of man, a "nearly perfect human being".<br /><br />The United States government, making the most of its one super-soldier, reimagined him as a superhero who served both as a counter-intelligence agent and a propaganda symbol to counter Nazi Germany's head of terrorist operations, the <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Red Skull">Red Skull</a>. To that end, Rogers was given a costume modeled after the American flag, a bulletproof shield, a personal sidearm and the codename Captain America. He was also given a cover identity as a clumsy infantry private at Camp LeHigh in Virginia. Barely out of his teens himself, Rogers then made friends with the teenage camp mascot, James Buchanan "Bucky" Barnes.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Captain_America_%28Steve_Rogers%29">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Captain_America_%28Steve_Rogers%29">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Captain_America">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Daredevil|Elektra|Hulk|Invisible Woman|Iron Man|Spider-Man|Thor|Wolverine</allies>		<enemies>Kingpin|Red Skull</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>		    <character origin="human" date="1939" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Captain Marvel</name>      <identity>William "Billy" Batson</identity>      <creator>C.C. Beck and Bill Parker</creator>      <company>Fawcett Comics (now DC Comics)</company>      <powers>Magically bestowed aspects of various mythological figures which include vast super-strength, invulnerability, super-speed, flight, fearlessness, and vast wisdom/enhanced mental perception.</powers>      <weakness>All Captain Marvels share power equally, immaturity.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Captain Marvel is a comic book superhero, originally published by Fawcett Comics and now owned by DC Comics. Created in 1939 by C.C. Beck and Bill Parker, the character first appeared in <em>Whiz Comics #2</em> (Feb, 1940). With a premise that taps into adolescent fantasy, Captain Marvel is the alter ego of Billy Batson, a youth who works as a radio news reporter and was chosen to be a champion of good by the wizard Shazam. Whenever Billy speaks the wizard's name, he is instantly struck by a magic lightning bolt that transforms him into an adult Superman-like hero empowered with the abilities of six mythological figures. Several friends and family members, most notably Marvel Family cohorts Mary Marvel and Captain Marvel, Jr., can share Billy's power and become "Marvels" themselves.<br /><br />Hailed as "The World's Mightiest Mortal" in his adventures (and nicknamed "The Big Red Cheese" by archvillain Doctor Sivana, an epithet adopted by fans as a nickname for their hero), Captain Marvel was, based on sales, the most popular superhero of the 1940s. The Captain Marvel Adventures series sold more copies during the mid-1940s than Superman and other competing superhero books.<br /><br />Fawcett ceased publishing Captain Marvel and Marvel Family comics in 1953. This was due to both a general decline in the popularity of superheroes and a copyright infringement suit from DC Comics alleging that Captain Marvel was an illegal infringment of <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Superman">Superman</a>. DC licensed the Marvel Family characters and returned them to publication in 1972, and acquired all rights to the characters in 1980. Captain Marvel and the Marvel Family have been integrated into the "DC Universe", and DC has attempted a few revivals. Despite their efforts, Captain Marvel has not regained widespread appeal with new generations.<br /><br />Like the classic depiction of <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Aquaman">Aquaman</a> or Superman, Marvel is usually an amiable, friendly person. Since he is still a youth, it is harder for him to become corrupted. However, Captain Marvel is also depicted as somewhat immature. Since Billy is only a teenager, he tends to take many things for granted and is usually nervous about interacting with other superheroes, making him seem like a case of arrested development to other heroes who are unaware of his true form. At one point, he got the <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Martian Manhunter">Martian Manhunter</a> addicted to Oreo cookies.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/secret_files/pdfs/captain_marvel.pdf">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/dc/SHAZAM.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Captain_Marvel_%28DC_Comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Batman|Flash|Green Arrow|Green Lantern|Hawkman|Martian Manhunter|Plastic Man|Superman|Wonder Woman</allies>		<enemies></enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="alien" date="1991" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Bronze" owner="Marvel" currently="Deceased">		<name>Carnage</name>      <identity>Cletus Kasady</identity>      <creator>David Michelinie and Mark Bagley</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Super-strength and endurance, ability to form blades and projectiles from symbiotic costume, symbiote allows all of Spider-Man's powers, web shooting is unlimited from Symbiote produced webbing, limited shapeshifting, cannot be detected by Spider sense.</powers>      <weakness>Heat, high frequency sounds.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Carnage (Cletus Kasady) is a fictional supervillain in the <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Spider-Man">Spider-Man</a> comic book published by Marvel Comics. He was created by comic book writer David Michelinie.<br /><br />Carnage was once serial killer Cletus Kasady, and became Carnage after merging with the offspring of the alien symbiote called <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Venom">Venom</a> during a prison breakout. The symbiote amplified his psychopathy and made him infinitely more dangerous. Unlike Venom, Carnage is a singular entity, referring to himself as "I" instead of "We", because the symbiote has actually merged into Kasady's bloodstream.<br /><br />Kasady believes he killed his father, who apparently killed the boy's mother when she tried to kill him; as he is completely insane, however, he is self-admittedly unclear on the exact details ("...or is it the other way around?"). It is also unclear on Kasady's relationship with his mother, as he seems to have feelings for her, causing him to dig up her grave at the end of Maximum Carnage. He also revealed that he killed his grandmother when he was younger, pushing her down a flight of stairs. He also tortured animals (including his own dog) when he was young. His largely self-invented past and personality is one of the many traits he shares with the <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Joker">Joker</a>, upon whom he is largely based.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Carnage">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/marvel/Carnage.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carnage_%28comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Invisible Woman|Silver Surfer|Spiderman|Venom</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1940" gender="female" morality="antihero" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Retired">		<name>Catwoman</name>      <identity>Selina Kyle</identity>      <creator>Bill Finger and Bob Kane</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>Above-average agility and dexterity, expertise in cat burglar training, steel spring-loaded climbing pitons and razor-sharp retractable nails allow her to scale vertical surfaces, wields an assortment of bullwhips and cat-o'-nine tails as gymnastic equipment.</powers>      <weakness>Limited mortality, emotional conflict.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Catwoman (real name Selina Kyle) is a DC Comics character created by Bill Finger and Bob Kane. She first appeared in Batman #1 (Spring, 1940), where she was initially known as "The Cat". Her name "Selina" derives from the ancient lunar deity Selene.<br /><br />Although originally introduced as an opponent for <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Batman">Batman</a>, Catwoman's status as hero or villain is ambiguous; she has her own moral code (she abhors killing, though has resorted to it at times) and has occasionally teamed up with Batman and other heroes against greater threats, even saving the lives of the entire Justice League on one occasion. She represents a gray area in Batman's otherwise black and white life where the line between good and evil blurs, and his attraction to her stems from this perception that, in her way, she's kind of a female version of himself: a dark, beautiful creature that prowls the night.<br /><br />It was revealed that Selina Kyle had been the wife of an abusive man, and eventually decided to leave her husband. However, her husband had kept her jewelry in his private vault, and she had to break into it to retrieve the jewelry. Selina enjoyed this experience so much she decided to become a professional costumed cat burglar, and thus began a career that would repeatedly lead to her encountering the Batman.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/secret_files/pdfs/catwoman.pdf">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/dc/Catwoman.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Catwoman">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Batman</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="altered" date="1964" gender="male" morality="antihero" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Jailed">		<name>Daredevil</name>      <identity>Matthew Michael Murdock</identity>      <creator>Frank Miller</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Superhuman senses (exc. sight), "radar sense", can read standard text by touch, expert acrobat and martial artist.</powers>      <weakness>Loud noises, blind.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Daredevil (alter ego Matthew Murdock) is a fictional superhero in the Marvel Comics universe. Created by writer Stan Lee and artist Bill Everett in <i>Daredevil Vol. 1, #1</i> (April 1964), he is notable as being among the few disabled superheroes.<br /><br />Irish-American Matthew Murdock was raised by single father and fading boxer "Battling Jack" Murdock in the Hell's Kitchen neighborhood of New York City. In the hopes of giving his son a better life than the one he led, the elder Murdock instilled in Matt the importance of education and non-violence. Matt, taunted by bullies who called the bookish youth "Daredevil" but unable to respond for fear of disappointing his father, vented his frustration and anger by working out in secret.<br /><br />While saving a blind man from an oncoming truck, Matt was blinded by radioactive material. Though the act of heroism had robbed him of his sight, Murdock found the radioactive exposure had heightened his remaining senses beyond normal human thresholds, and had additionally given him a sixth "radar sense", as he termed it, that enabled him to detect the shape and location of objects around him. A mysterious man named Stick became the young Murdock's mentor, teaching him how to control his new abilities while honing the youth's natural aptitude in acrobatics and martial arts.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Daredevil">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/Daredevil.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daredevil_%28Marvel_Comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Captain America|Elektra|Iron Man|Spider-Man|Wolverine</allies>		<enemies>Kingpin|Punisher</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="alien" date="1970" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Silver" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Darkseid</name>      <identity>Uxas</identity>      <creator>Jack Kirby</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>Seemingly limitless superhuman strength, speed and stamina, invulnerability, genius level intellect, master planner and tactician, matter transmution, energy projection, mind control, 'Omega-Effect', teleportation, time travel, flight, energy draining, possibly unkillable, can survive in space unaided.</powers>      <weakness>Obsession to get even with people who have gotten the better of him.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Darkseid is a DC Comics supervillain created by Jack Kirby, originally as part of <em>The Fourth World</em> series of comic books in the early 1970s. He has risen in popularity and become one of the most powerful and well-known villains of DC Comics.<br /><br />Darkseid is the ruler of the planet Apokolips, a post he obtained after assassinating his mother. He is obsessed with finding the Anti-Life Equation in order to use it to rule the universe. This goal also includes conquering his rival planet, New Genesis, ruled by the Highfather, formerly Izaya the Inheritor. The resulting destructive war is stopped only with a diplomatic exchange of the Highfather's and Darkseid's infant sons. Darkseid's Orion is surrendered to the Highfather while Darkseid receives Scott Free, who will later become the master escape artist Mister Miracle. This turns out to be a setback for Darkseid with his biological son growing up to fiercely value and defend the ideals of New Genesis in opposition to his father.<br /><br />Darkseid is a character whose personality can vaguely be described as evil incarnate. Darkseid is not merely content to control but to dominate those individuals under him into totally obedient and morally corrupt caricatures of individuals. Apokolips is a world that resembles Hell because of his need to be worshipped as a god and the need to nurture the most horrible aspects of the human spirit. On Apokolips, his subjects are raised in a personality cult, to venerate him, to sacrifice themselves gladly in his name. Darkseid's great ambition is to wipe out free will from the universe and reshape it in his own image. To this end, he seeks to unravel the mysterious 'Anti-Life Equation', which will allow him to control completely the thoughts and emotions of living beings.<br /><br />Darkseid seems to possess a twisted form of honor but this code is 'flexible' depending on his mood. It seems he desires to be thought of as an honorable being but never lets this stand in the way of his gaining power or revenge. He especially takes delight in seeing the mighty brought low whether in strength or moral conviction. Darkseid's primary weakness may be his obsession to get even with people who have gotten the better of him, especially <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Superman">Superman</a>, and the New Gods. </p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/secret_files/pdfs/darkseid.pdf">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/dc/Darkseid.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Darkseid">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Lex Luthor|Shadow-Thief</allies>		<enemies>Aquaman|Batman|Black Canary|Flash|Green Arrow|Green Lantern|Hawkman|Martian Manhunter|Plastic Man|Superman|Wonder Woman</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1933" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Platinum" owner="CondeNast" currently="Missing">		<name>Doc Savage</name>      <identity>Doctor Clark Savage, Jr.</identity>      <creator>Lester Dent</creator>      <company>Street and Smith Publications</company>      <powers>Peak physical abilities.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Doc Savage, whose real name is "Doctor. Clark Savage, Jr.", also known as "the Man of Bronze", is a physician, surgeon, scientist, adventurer, inventor, explorer, researcher and musician - a renaissance man. A team of scientists (assembled by his father) trained his mind and body to near-superhuman abilities almost from birth, giving him great strength and endurance, a photographic memory, mastery of the martial arts, and vast knowledge of the sciences. "He rights wrongs and punishes evildoers."<br /><br />He resides on the top floor of a New York City skyscraper, implicitly the Empire State Building. Doc owns a fleet of cars, trucks, aircraft, and boats which he stores at a secret hangar on the Hudson River, under the name The Hidalgo Trading Company. He sometimes retreats to his Fortress of Solitude in the Arctic. All of this is paid for with gold from a Central American mine the natives gave his father and his father left to him.<br /><br />In early stories some of the criminals captured by Doc received "a delicate brain operation" to cure their criminal tendencies. The criminals returned to society fully productive and unaware of their criminal past. A non-canonical comic book series published in the 1980s states these were actually lobotomies.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://thepulp.net/docsavage.html">ThePulp.Net</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/indi/DocSavage.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Doc_savage">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Red Skull</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="altered" date="1962" gender="male" morality="nblurred" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Doctor Doom</name>      <identity>Victor von Doom</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee and Jack Kirby</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Super-genius, Can exchange consciousness with another humanoid, command of magic, wears a custom-designed suit of powered armor at all times.</powers>      <weakness>Overconfidence, obsessed with Mr. Fantastic, power-hungery.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Doctor Doom, real name Victor von Doom, is a Marvel Comics supervillain. Created by Stan Lee and Jack Kirby, he debuted in <em>The Fantastic Four #5</em> (July 1962). His full origin was told in <em>Fantastic Four Annual #2</em> (1964).<br /><br />A brilliant scientist, Doom was once a classmate of the Fantastic Four's Reed Richards. However, he became embittered by his jealousy of Richards and by facial scars received from an experiment gone awry, and perhaps from impatiently donning a steaming-hot iron mask forged by mystic monks.<br /><br />While a child, he discovered his mother's magical artifacts and von Doom began his studies into the occult as well as developing his innate scientific abilities. His astounding reputation came to the attention of the dean of science at State University in America, and von Doom was offered a full scholarship. At State, von Doom first met both <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Mister Fantastic">Reed Richards</a> and <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Thing">Ben Grimm</a>, two men who would go on to become his enemies in later years as Mister Fantastic and the Thing, respectively. Richards, in particular, represented a substantial threat to Doom's self-perceived superiority. Doom began conducting hazardous extra-dimensional experiments.<br /><br />Doctor Doom's plans are fueled by his ego and his conviction that he is not only capable of world domination, but also worthy and deserving of it. While he is utterly heartless and places little value on the lives of others, he also follows a strict code of honor. Several times he has struck bargains with various characters in the Marvel Universe, and he has always upheld those bargains, honoring his word and following through with his promises to the letter. He is a cruel and ruthless dictator; yet while he rules his nation of Latveria with an iron fist and is willing to deliver swift and cruel punishments, he also treats his subjects fairly (as long as they acknowledge his absolute rule) and at times has even put himself at risk to protect his kingdom and subjects. This complexity has made him one of the more interesting characters in the Marvel Universe.<br /><br />Doom is considered the archenemy of the Fantastic Four, but has also been added to the rogue galleries of the Avengers, the <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Punisher">Punisher</a>, the <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Silver Surfer">Silver Surfer</a>, the <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Hulk">Hulk</a>, <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Iron Man">Iron Man</a> and <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Spider-Man">Spider-Man</a>. He is one of the comic book industry's most recognizable and archetypal supervillains. His ruling of the small nation of Latveria provides him with diplomatic immunity, an ingenious element never previously used in comic books.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Doctor_Doom_%28Victor_von_Doom%29">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/marvel/DrDoomI.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Doctor_Doom">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Namor</allies>		<enemies>Galactus|Invisible Woman|Iron Man|Silver Surfer|Spider-Man|Thanos</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1963" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Doctor Octopus</name>      <identity>Otto Octavius</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee and Steve Ditko</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Brilliant engineer and inventor, mechanical appendages capable of lifting massive objects and scaling walls, low level telepathy.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal, nearly blind.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Doctor Octopus (Otto Octavius) is a Marvel Comics supervillain, an enemy of Spider-Man. Created by writer Stan Lee and artist Steve Ditko, he first appeared in <em>Amazing Spider-Man #3</em> (July 1963).<br /><br />A highly intelligent mad scientist, he is obsessed with proving his own genius and destroying his arch foe. Although possibly overshadowed by the <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Green Goblin">Green Goblin</a> and <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Venom">Venom</a> in various eras, Doctor Octopus is possibly <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Spider-Man">Spider-Man</a>'s greatest adversary.<br /><br />Doctor Octopus has been hinted as being a low-level telepathic mutant, but no superpowers have been outrightly revealed. He is a bona fide genius in the fields of atomic physics, in which he holds a Ph.D in robotics.<br /><br />His harness is attached to four mentally controlled, prehensile metallic appendages. These arms are capable of lifting up to three tons each, provided at least one arm is used to support his body. The reaction time and agility of his mechanical appendages is enhanced far beyond the range attainable for normal human musculature. The arms allow Octavius to move rapidly over any terrain and to scale vertical surfaces and ceilings. He has developed his concentration and control to the point that he can engage a single opponent, like Spider-Man, or multiple opponents with the arms while performing a completely separate task, such as drinking a cup of coffee or constructing a machine.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Doctor_Octopus">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.spider-bob.com/villains/marvel/DrOctopusI.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Doctor_Octopus">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Spider-Man</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1963" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Doctor Strange</name>      <identity>Johann Schmidt</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee and Steve Ditko</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Able to wield magic to an almost infinite number of effects, commonly including mystic bolts, teleportation, illusions, spells and astral projection.</powers>      <weakness>No blatant weaknesses.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Doctor Strange is a fictional comic-book sorcerer and superhero in the Marvel Comics universe. Created by writer-editor Stan Lee and artist Steve Ditko, he first appeared in <em>Strange Tales #110</em> (July 1963). Additionally, the name had been used for a different Marvel character two months earlier.<br /><br />Dr. Stephen Strange is the Sorcerer Supreme of the Earth dimension, responsible for defending it from mystic threats. He is a master of the mystic arts, using his abilities to battle evil magicians and other supernatural villains. He is also often consulted by other superheroes on supernatural matters.<br /><br />He became an accomplished but arrogant surgeon until he suffered subtle, though profound, neurological damage in an automobile accident in 1963. Unable to continue his profession and too hubristic to accept subordinate medical assignments, he became unemployed and destitute. Learning of a hermit called the Ancient One who could possibly cure him, the desperate Strange ventured to the man's isolated Himalayan abode and asked for aid. The Ancient One instead offered to take on Strange as an apprentice. Strange refused, but could not leave immediately due to a sudden blizzard.<br /><br />Doctor Strange's magic has shown the ability to effect even the most powerful of entities, leading many to believe Dr. Strange is Marvel's most powerful superhero.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Doctor_Strange_%28Stephen_Strange%29">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/DrStrangeII.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dr_Strange">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies></enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="alien" date="1992" gender="male" morality="nblurred" era="Bronze" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Doomsday</name>      <identity>The Ultimate</identity>      <creator>Dan Jurgens</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>Vast super strength, invulnerability, endurance, stamina, and reflexes. Enhanced healing and regenerative ability, high willpower, regenerates even after death, immune to whatever circumstance killed it and becomes resistant to anything that injures or harms him.</powers>      <weakness>Any weakness is compensated for upon next resurrection.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Doomsday is the name of a fictional supervillain in the <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Superman">Superman</a> comic book series best known for fighting and killing Superman.<br /><br />Doomsday was artificially created in the distant past on the planet Krypton by a mad scientist named Bertron, who wished to create the ultimate lifeform. To do so, Bertron and his team sent a baby onto the surface of Krypton, where it would be killed by the harsh environment or the vicious creatures inhabiting it. Each time, the lifeform's remains were harvested and used again, to create a better, stronger version than the previous. In short, the mad scientist was using the method of cloning to accelerate the evolution of the being he was creating. Through decades of this process, the being which would eventually become Doomsday was forced to endure the agony of death, thousands upon thousands of times; the memory of these countless deaths was recorded in his genes and drove it to hate all life. Bertron himself met his death at the hands of his own creation.<br /><br />Doomsday's physical abilities perhaps even surpass Superman. Doomsday's strength has no known limits and is such that he can easily move and lift weights in excess of 200000 tons. His other abilities include extreme resistance to heat, cold, and injury allowing him to survive on the most inhospitable worlds as well as survive in the vacuum of space. Doomsday possesses almost inexhaustable endurance and stamina. Superman once remarked on Doomsday, "We've been fighting all day and Doomsday doesn't seem to have slowed down". Most surprising is his reflexes and speed for his size.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/dc/Doomsday.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Doomsday_%28comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Darkseid|Superman</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1981" gender="female" morality="antihero" era="Bronze" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Elektra</name>      <identity>Elektra Natchios</identity>      <creator>Frank Miller</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Exotic martial arts and bladed weapons.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Elektra Natchios is a Marvel Comics character. Created by Frank Miller, she first appeared in <em>Daredevil #168</em> (January 1981).<br /><br />Elektra is a ninja and assassin who wields two bladed sais as her trademark weapon. She was a love interest of the superhero <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Daredevil">Daredevil</a>, but her violent nature and mercenary lifestyle divided the two. She is one of Frank Miller's best-loved creations for Marvel, and subsequent writers' use of her is controversial among American comic book fans, although she has often been used as a supporting character of the X-Men's <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Wolverine">Wolverine</a>.<br /><br />Elektra lost faith and hope. She quit Columbia and returned to the study of martial arts. Stick, a member of the benevolent organization called the Chaste, recognized the darkness in her soul and attempted to train her himself, but she ultimately sided with the Hand, a sect of mystical ninja, who trained her as an assassin. She later broke away from them and became an independent agent, and in this role she again encountered Matt Murdock, who was now active as Daredevil. She soon learned of his double identity, and although the pair worked together to fight the Hand, they also came into conflict frequently.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Elektra">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/marvel/Elektra.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elektra_%28comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Daredevil</allies>		<enemies>Kingpin</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="altered" date="1940" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Flash</name>      <identity>Jay Garrick, Barry Allen, and Wally West</identity>      <creator>Gardner Fox and Harry Lampert</creator>      <company>All-American Publications (now DC Comics)</company>      <powers>Super-sonic speed, become intangible by vibrating molecular mass, limited time and inter-dimensional travel.</powers>      <weakness>Limited amounts of energy.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The Flash is a DC Comics superhero. Created by Gardner Fox and Harry Lampert, the original Flash first appeared in <em>Flash Comics #1</em> (1940).<br /><br />Nicknamed the Scarlet Speedster, The Flash possesses "super-speed", which includes the ability to run and move extremely fast, use superhuman reflexes and violate certain laws of physics. Thus far, three different characters, each of whom somehow gained the power of "super-speed," have assumed the identity of the Flash: Jay Garrick (1940-present), Barry Allen (1956-86), and Wally West (1987-present).<br /><br />Jay Garrick, a college student who gained his speed through the inhalation of hard water vapors (later retconned into heavy water vapors), and who wore a winged metal helmet reminiscent of the mythological Roman god Mercury. He is notable as the first super-speedster in comics, and one of the first to have a singular super-power as opposed to the multi-powered <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Superman">Superman</a>.<br /><br />Barry Allen, a police scientist who gained super-speed when bathed by chemicals after a shelf of them was struck by lightning. Wally West, Allen's nephew by marriage, gained the Flash's powers through an accident identical to Allen's.<br /><br />All incarnations of the Flash can run and move their limbs at superhuman speeds, and possess superhuman reflexes. All possess an aura that prevents air friction from affecting their bodies and clothes while moving. West can vibrate through objects; in the past, West would cause whatever he vibrated through to explode, but has recently shown this to be a controlled ability as he can pass through objects without any ensuing explosion. Although not nearly as precise as Allen when he used his cosmic treadmill, West has shown to be able to traverse time and dimensions with his own powers, like Allen in <em>Showcase #4</em> in 1956.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/secret_files/pdfs/flash.pdf">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/dc/FlashI.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flash_%28comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Aquaman|Batman|Black Canary|Green Arrow|Green Lantern|Hawkman|Martian Manhunter|Plastic Man|Superman|Wonder Woman</allies>		<enemies>Shade|Vandal Savage</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="alien" date="1966" gender="male" morality="nblurred" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Galactus</name>      <identity>Galan</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee and Jack Kirby</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Imbued with the Power Cosmic which can enable any number of abilities.</powers>      <weakness>Must maintain an energy source, must be contained within his armor or will explode into a star.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Galactus, sometimes called the Devourer of Worlds or Eater of Planets, is a fictional comic book character, a cosmic entity within Marvel Comics' universe. Created by Jack Kirby and Stan Lee, he first appeared in <em>Fantastic Four #48</em>, the beginning of a story arc sometimes regarded as the finest Lee/Kirby collaboration.<br /><br />Galactus wields the immeasurable Power Cosmic (indeed, he is so powerful that he must always wear his alien armor in order to contain his vast energies; were he ever to remove it his energy would radiate outwards uncontrollably giving him the appearance of a star). It has even been speculated by some that when sated his power is far beyond the level of even the Celestials. However, he must feed to survive, consuming the energy of entire planets. Towards this end, Galactus scours the universe seeking planets to sustain himself.<br /><br />Over millions of years, he has become one of the most feared beings in the universe, his vast power allowing him to lay waste to innumerable extra-terrestrial civilizations in his quest for sustenance.<br /><br />Nevertheless, he is not an evil being, but rather a force of nature whose feedings are necessary for survival. It is known that Galactus plays a necessary role in the continuum of the Universe, bringing balance between the two opposing universal forces of Death and Eternity; which are essentially the Yin and Yang of the Marvel universe. It has been said the universe would eventually fail, collapsing under it's own weight without Galactus' presence to balance it. Presumably this process would not be immediate but happen gradually over time. It has been suggested by some that his purpose in the universe is to devour planets that have reached an evolutionary peak, although alternative information suggests that he will create a whole new universe at the end of this one, which will be indescribably greater than the total of the planets he has taken into himself.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Galactus">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/gods_monsters/marvel/Galactus.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galactus">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Captain America|Hulk|Invisible Woman|Iron Man|Silver Surfer|Thor</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="mutant" date="1990" gender="male" morality="nblurred" era="Bronze" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Gambit</name>      <identity>Remy LeBeau</identity>      <creator>Chris Claremont and Jim Lee</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Transmute air into poisonous gas, formerly converting the potential energy of any object into explosive kinetic energy by touching it, hypnotic charm causes others to trust him.</powers>      <weakness>Women.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Gambit is the codename of Remy LeBeau, a mutant comic book character in the fictional Marvel Universe. He has the ability to turn the potential energy of objects into kinetic energy, usually causing them to explode. He first appeared in <em>Uncanny X-Men #266</em> (August 1990).<br /><br />Gambit can charge inanimate objects with kinetic energy giving them explosive power. One of his trademark tricks is to hurl playing cards at an opponent, charging each card and turning it into a deadly projectile. His other tricks have included charging a wad of chewing gum when he was otherwise entirely tied up and charging the floor of an entire room, causing it to explode with great force.<br /><br />He often wields an adamantium telescopic staff and has enhanced agility and stamina. On several occasions he has shown an ability to charm people through mild hypnosis and seems able to scramble attempts at mind reading and psychic attacks because of the charged potential energy always in his body. This charming ability may not be a result of hypnosis but appears to have the potential to be an empathy-based power. It has been mentioned that it becomes less effective to people who are aware of this ability.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Gambit">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/Gambit.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gambit_(comics)">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Iceman|Phoenix|Professor X|Psylocke|Rogue|Wolverine</allies>		<enemies>Apocalypse|Juggernaut|Magneto|Mystique</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="hybrid" date="1972" gender="male" morality="nblurred" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Ghost Rider</name>      <identity>John Blaze</identity>      <creator>Roy Thomas and Gary Friedrich</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Possesses supernatural strength and durability, rides a mystical flame cycle that can travel across any surface and attain incredible speeds, can use his Penance Stare which forces those who meet his gaze to experience the pain they have caused others, can project both regular and ethereal flame offensively, he also wields a magical chain which offers many forms of attack.</powers>      <weakness>Hell fire.</weakness>	  <copy><p>John Blaze was born into a world of motorcycle grease and cheering crowds. The son of Barton Blaze and Naomi Kale, Johnny spent his early years in the Quentin Carnival, where his parents starred in a stunt show with Craig "Crash" Simpson. His idyllic home life ended abruptly, however, when Naomi abandoned John, taking his younger siblings - Barbara and Daniel - with her. Naomi's decision to leave had been difficult, but she felt it was necessary because of the family curse. She feared that her own firstborn would suffer in the same way that she had, so she left him behind and placed her other children in the care of a woman named Francis Ketch.<br /><br />One night after Crash's death, Johnny found himself transformed into a skeletal being with a flaming skull. Fearing at first that this demonic form was a manifestation of his own evil side, he soon realized that he had bonded with some wholly separate entity. This merger of Johnny Blaze and a demonic force became known as the Ghost Rider, which amused Mephisto greatly. Transforming nightly into the Ghost Rider, John became involved with a local motorcycle gang, Satan's Servants. Their leader, Curly Samuels, had gained the Ghost Rider's trust, until a shocked John discovered that the soul of Crash Simpson lurked within Curly's form. Mephisto had offered Crash a new life in exchange for betraying his adopted son, and Crash had eagerly accepted. The Ghost Rider's spirit was cast into Hell, where he managed to reawaken Crash's sense of honor and love.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Ghost_Rider_(John_Blaze)">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/GhostRiderVII.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ghost_Rider">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies></enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1941" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Green Arrow</name>      <identity>Oliver Jonas "Ollie" Queen</identity>      <creator>Mort Weisinger and George Papp</creator>      <company>More Fun Comics (now DC Comics)</company>      <powers>No superhuman powers. Master archer with large selection of specialized trick arrows, hand-to-hand combat training.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal, women.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Green Arrow (Oliver Jonas "Ollie" Queen) is a DC Comics superhero. Created by Mort Weisinger and George Papp, he first appeared in <em>More Fun Comics #73</em> (1941).<br /><br />Dressed like Robin Hood, Green Arrow is an archer, who invents arrows with various special functions, such as a glue arrow, a net arrow, a boxing glove arrow, etc. Green Arrow's code against outright killing is established firmly, with the development of trick arrows to subdue or outwit opponents. Originally, most of his other traits were borrowed from <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Batman">Batman</a>. Like the Caped Crusader, Green Arrow was a millionaire, mentored a young sidekick (Speedy) and policed a fictional metropolis (Star City).<br /><br />Throughout his first twenty-five years, Green Arrow was not a significant hero. But in the late 1960s, after he lost his fortune, writers gave him the unique role of streetwise crusader for the working class and the underprivileged. In 1970, he was paired with the more law-and-order-oriented hero Green Lantern in a groundbreaking, socially conscious comic book series. Since then, he has been popular among comic book fans and most writers have taken an urban, gritty approach to the character.<br /><br />The Green Arrow character was inspired by a few different sources, including Edgar Wallace's The Green Archer (and the 1940 Columbia Pictures serial of the same name based on the novel), and Fawcett Publications' earlier archery-themed hero Golden Arrow. Green Arrow was also obviously created as an archery-themed version of the earlier character Batman, as several similarities between the two characters can be spotted, especially in Green Arrow's earlier incarnation: Green Arrow had a teenaged sidekick named Speedy just as Batman has Robin; Green Arrow and Batman were/are both millionaire playboys in their secret identities; Green Arrow had an Arrowcar and an Arrowplane similar to Batman's Batmobile and Batplane; while Batman is summoned to police headquarters by the Bat-signal, Green Arrow was summoned by the Arrow-signal. The Arrowcar was yellow in color and shaped reminiscent of the land-speed record holder of the 1920s, the British Golden Arrow. (These were allegedly inspired after his meeting with Batman in their early careers, where the two of them thwarted an attempt to trigger a war).</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/secret_files/pdfs/green_arrow.pdf">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/dc/GreenArrowI.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Green_Arrow">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Aquaman|Batman|Black Canary|Flash|Green Lantern|Hawkman|Martian Manhunter|Plastic Man|Superman|Wonder Woman</allies>		<enemies>Shade</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="altered" date="1964" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Green Goblin</name>      <identity>Norman Osborn Sr.</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee and Steve Ditko</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Superhuman strength, regenerative healing factor, various weapons, great intelligence.</powers>      <weakness>Insanity.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The Green Goblin is a Marvel Comics supervillain who is considered an arch-nemesis of <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Spider-Man">Spider-Man</a>. The Green Goblin dresses in a garish green and purple costume resembling a goblin and uses an arsenal of high-tech weapons, notably grenade-like "pumpkin bombs", and rides on a personal flying device often resembling a bat but originally resembling a broomstick. The Green Goblin was created by Stan Lee and Steve Ditko in <em>Amazing Spider-Man #14</em> (July 1964).<br /><br />The original Goblin was Norman Osborn, a ruthless industrialist who co-founded a major firm with Dr. Mendel Stromm. To seize total control, Osborn had Stromm framed for embezzlement and then searched his possessions, discovering an experimental strength/intelligence enhancement formula. When Osborn attempted to create the serum, it turned green and exploded in his face. The accident changed Osborn, greatly increasing his intelligence and strength, but also drove him insane.<br /><br />Osborn adopted the bizarre identity of the Green Goblin with the goal of becoming the Boss of the city's organized crime. This was intended to be complemented by defeating Spider-Man, a relatively low-powered opponent whom he was confident he could defeat to enhance his reputation. To this end, Osborn created a personal flying device, which started in a broomstick-like shape and evolved into his Goblin Glider, and hand grenade-like explosive weapons resembling pumpkins, a number of thrown projectile weapons called Razor-Bats featuring sharp blades (much like a certain Batman's batarangs), and blaster equipped gloves which fired energy blasts from the finger tips.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Green_Goblin_%28Norman_Osborn%29">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/marvel/GreenGoblinI.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Green_Goblin">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Spiderman</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1940" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Green Lantern</name>      <identity>Alan Scott</identity>      <creator>Martin Nodell and Bill Finger</creator>      <company>All-American Publications (now DC Comics)</company>      <powers>Green Lantern Ring enhanced abilities granting the wielder the ability to create forms and devices of green energy from their imagination, transmute materials, phase through solid objects, become invisible, fly at supersonic speeds, superhuman strength, speed, stamina, durability, immunity to harsh environments, communicate with all known sentient species.</powers>      <weakness>Power Ring is limited to a 24 hour charge, yellow objects, wood.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Several characters have taken the mantle of Green Lantern throughout the years. Each possessed a "power ring"  that gives the user great control over the physical world as long as the wielder has sufficient willpower. While the ring of the Golden Age Green Lantern (Alan Scott) was magically powered, the rings worn by all subsequent Lanterns were the creations of the Guardians of the Universe who granted such rings to worthy candidates across the universe. These individuals made up the intergalactic police force known as the Green Lantern Corps.<br /><br />Air force pilot Hal Jordan took the role of Green Lantern and was eventually teamed up with <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Green Arrow">Green Arrow</a>, in ground-breaking, socially conscious series that pitted the sensibilities of the law-and-order-orientated Lantern with the populist Green Arrow. In the last twenty years, DC has placed different individuals in the role of Earth's Green Lantern, most prominently John Stewart, Guy Gardner and Kyle Rayner.<br /><br />Green Lantern has proven to be one of DC's most popular superheroes. Each Green Lantern was a member of the Justice Society of America or the Justice League.<br /><br />Scott, like the other Green Lanterns, owes his powers to the Guardians of the Universe. The magic that gave Scott's lantern its power came from a collection of wild magic known as the Star Heart. The Star Heart was all the wild magic in the universe, which the Guardians gathered together in an attempt to ensure a more orderly universe.<br /><br />All Green Lanterns wield a power ring that can generate a variety of effects and energy constructs, sustained purely by the ring wearer's strength of will. The greater the user's willpower, the more effective the ring. The limits of the power ring's abilities are not clearly defined and it has been referred to as "the most powerful weapon in the universe" on more than one occasion. Across the years, the ring has been shown capable of accomplishing anything within the imagination of the ring bearer.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/secret_files/pdfs/green_lantern.pdf">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/dc/GreenLanternII.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Green_Lantern">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Aquaman|Batman|Black Canary|Flash|Green Arrow|Hawkman|Martian Manhunter|Plastic Man|Superman|Wonder Woman</allies>		<enemies>Parallax</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1940" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Missing">		<name>Hawkman</name>      <identity>Carter Hall</identity>      <creator>Gardner Fox and Dennis Neville</creator>      <company>Flash Comics (now DC Comics)</company>      <powers>Nth metal allowing flight, sharp eyesight, withstand cold temperatures, regeneration, enhanced strength, artificial feather wings, archaic weaponry.</powers>      <weakness>Powerless without gear.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Hawkman is a comic book superhero in the DC Comics universe. He is characterized by a costume with large artificial wings on a harness, and a belt with a special metal which allows him to fly. He often uses archaic weaponry to fight crime.<br /><br />Thousands of years ago, Egyptian Prince Khufu and his lover, came into contact with Nth (ninth) metal, an element from the planet Thanagar.  Exposure to the extraterrestrial material imprinted racial memories from the alien Thanagarians onto the couple and combined with their true love, strengthened their souls and the bond between them.<br /><br />Soon after their exposure to Nth metal, the lovers were murdered by Hath-Set, a corrupt priest of Anubis.  Over subsequent, and mostly unrevealed lifetimes, Khufu and Chay-Ara were reborn again and again, destined to meet and fall in love.<br /><br />In the middle of the 20th century, Khufu was reborn as the independently wealthy Carter Hall, who after handling an Egyptian knife, realized his true lineage and continued his quest for vengeance against his murderer Hath-Set, reborn as Anton Hastor.  Utilizing the antigravity Nth metal to construct an anti-gravity belt and wing harness in tribute to the Egyptian hawk god Horus, he adopted ancient weapons of war, becoming Hawkman.<br /><br />Hawkman was a charter member of the Justice Society of America, and became their permanent chairman, following The <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Flash">Flash</a> and <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Green Lantern">Green Lantern</a>. While a member of the Justice League of America he often verbally sparred with the iconoclastic liberal hero <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Green Arrow">Green Arrow</a>.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/secret_files/pdfs/hawkman.pdf">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/dc/HawkmanI.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hawkman">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Aquaman|Batman|Black Canary|Flash|Green Arrow|Green Lantern|Martian Manhunter|Plastic Man|Superman|Wonder Woman</allies>		<enemies>Shadow Theif|Vandal Savage</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="demon" date="1993" gender="male" morality="antihero" era="Bronze" owner="DarkHorse" currently="Active">		<name>Hellboy</name>      <identity>Anung Un Rama</identity>      <creator>Mike Mignola</creator>      <company>Dark Horse Comics</company>      <powers>Knowledge and experience of fighting the supernatural, superhuman strength, heals quickly, stone Right Hand of Doom is key to the end of the world, Crown of the Apocalypse</powers>      <weakness>No blatant weaknesses.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Hellboy is dubbed the "World's Greatest Paranormal Investigator". He is a large red-skinned demon with a tail, horns broken off to stumps (which some fans mistook for goggles in early issues) and a big stone right hand (the Right Hand of Doom). Created by Mike Mignola, Hellboy's adventures have been chronicled in a sequence of comic book mini-series published by Dark Horse Comics.<br /><br />Mignola's stories are heavily influenced by, and have been dedicated to, H. P. Lovecraft, Jack Kirby, Edgar Allan Poe, and other authors. Horror stories of the Weird Tales variety are another important influence. Writer Robert Bloch has praised Hellboy as one of the most innovative and entertaining comics in recent years. Certain Hellboy stories also draw on folklore from Ireland, Norway, Russia, Malaysia, and Japan, among other countries.<br /><br />Hellboy is a creature summoned in the final months of World War II by a fictional version of Grigori Rasputin, on a small island just off the coast of Scotland ('Tarmagent Island'), having been commissioned by the Nazis to change the tide of war ("Project Ragna Rok"). Hellboy appeared in a fireball in a ruined church in East Bromwich, England, December 23, 1944. He proved not to be a devil, but a little boy-like creature (with red skin, horns, a tail, and a large stone right hand) - hence the name given by Professor Trevor Bruttenholm (pronounced Broom).<br /><br />Hellboy's superhuman abilities stem from his demonic nature. While his specific powers and abilities have never been explicitly described in the comics, Hellboy is much stronger and tougher than an ordinary human being. Hellboy is not invulnerable, but he is extremely tough. He has been savagely beaten by large monsters on several occasions and survived, often with relatively few injuries. On one occasion, he directly charged an MG-42 machine gun and took numerous bullets to the chest before destroying the gun.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/indi/Hellboy.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hellboy">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies></enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="altered" date="1962" gender="male" morality="antihero" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Hulk</name>      <identity>Dr. Bruce Banner</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee and Jack Kirby</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Vast superhuman strength, stamina, and durability, able to leap miles within a single bound, regenerative healing factor, ability to see astral bodies, absorbs radiation, transformation</powers>      <weakness>Blind rage, over-angering causes a reversion to human form.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Dr. Robert Bruce Banner is a military scientist working on developing a new type of weapon called a "Gamma Bomb". As the bomb is being tested, however, Bruce notices that a teenager, Rick Jones, has driven his hot rod onto the test site. Banner leaves the safety of his bunker, grabs the young man, and throws him into a nearby ditch, but the bomb explodes before Bruce himself can get to safety. As a result, he absorbs an enormous dose of gamma radiation, and this is what causes him to transform into the rampaging Hulk.<br /><br />At first Bruce becomes the "Grey Hulk" whenever the sun goes down, but after being exposed to further radiation in space, he begins transforming into the larger, more destructive Green Hulk whenever he grows angry, frightened, or panicked. Whereas the Grey Hulk seemed to possess normal human intelligence and an arrogant, dismissive attitude toward "puny humans," the Green Hulk has the intellect and temperament of a small, angry child.<br /><br />Many of the early Hulk stories involve General Thunderbolt Ross continually trying to capture or destroy the Hulk, with his "Hulkbuster" U.S. Army battalion at his side. Ross's daughter Betty is in love with Bruce Banner and often criticizes her father for pursuing the Hulk so relentlessly. Meanwhile, General Ross's right-hand man, Major Glenn Talbot, is in love with Betty, and is torn between pursuing the Hulk or trying to gain Betty's love in a more honorable way. Teenager Rick Jones served as the Hulk's friend and sidekick for a time. Later, another teenager named Jim Wilson also befriends the Hulk.<br /><br />The Hulk has shown a high resistance to physical damage nearly regardless of the cause (whether it be artillery shells or falls from a great height), and has also shown resistance to extreme temperatures, poisons, and diseases. In addition, the Hulk's body can regenerate damaged or destroyed areas of tissue at an amazing rate.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Hulk_%28Bruce_Banner%29">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/HulkII.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Incredible_Hulk">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Captain America|Invisible Woman|Spider-Man|THor</allies>		<enemies>Apocalypse|Iron Man|Wolverine</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="altered" date="1961" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Human Torch</name>      <identity>Jonathan Lowell Spencer "Johnny" Storm</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee and Jack Kirby</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Pyrokinesis, flight, absorption of heat energy.</powers>      <weakness>Immature, lack of oxygen, sufficient quantities of water, flame retardant foam, vacuum environments.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The Human Torch (Jonathan Lowell Spencer "Johnny" Storm) is a comic book superhero in the Marvel Universe associated with the Fantastic Four. The Human Torch first appeared in <em>Fantastic Four #1</em> and was created by Stan Lee and Jack Kirby.<br /><br />As a result of the cosmic ray exposure during the space flight he took with his sister, <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Invisible Woman">Susan</a>, along with <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Mister Incredible">Reed Richards</a> and <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Thing">Ben Grimm</a>, Johnny gained a spectacular set of powers: he can envelop himself in flame at will (often exclaiming his catch-phrase, "Flame on!"), which allows him to fly, shoot flame offensively, and absorb heat energy. Naturally the Torch is invulnerable to his own flame.<br /><br />The Torch's primary power is to envelop himself in, and manipulate fire. The Human Torch can direct this flame as a blast of superheated plasma, or manipulate it for various shapes, temperatures, or effects. He can absorb flame into his body, or extinguish ambient flame at will. The Torch has the ability to fly at nearly the speed of sound, and has sufficient ambient heat to vaporize projectiles that approach him. The Torch has been observed to vaporize rocks, bottles, bullets, and even steel girders in fractions of a second; yet this ambient heat does not extend beyond his body, or ignite objects in proximity to him. The uppermost level of The Human Torch's power is his "Nova Flame," which is usually released omni-directionally and reaches temperatures of 1,000,000 degrees. Any level lower than this cannot burn him.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Human_Torch_(Johnny_Storm)">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/HumanTorchII.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_Torch">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Captain America|Hulk|Invisible Woman|Iron Man|Mister Fantastic|Spider-Man|Thing|Thor|Wolverine</allies>		<enemies>Doctor Doom|Galactus</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="mutant" date="1963" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Iceman</name>      <identity>Robert "Bobby" Louis Drake</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee and Jack Kirby</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Thermokinesis, enabling local and body temperature reduction, hydrokinesis, cryokinesis, thermal vision.</powers>      <weakness>Fire, lack of water supply.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Iceman is a comic book superhero in the Marvel Comics universe and an original and current member of the X-Men. Created by Stan Lee and Jack Kirby, he first appeared in <em>X-Men volume 1 #1</em> (September, 1963).<br /><br />Iceman is a mutant with the ability to emanate intense cold which can condense moisture from the air as ice formations and the mental ability to shape those ice formations into whatever structure he can imagine. He is often seen to project cold from his hands in the form of "ice blasts" which can cause an enemy to be completely engulfed in ice in a matter of seconds. Perhaps his most ingenious use of his abilities is the creation of a sort of ice ramp along which he can slide very quickly. This can occasionally lead to him being confused with the <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Silver Surfer">Silver Surfer</a>, as the two characters are visually quite similar.<br /><br />Over the years, his mutant physiology has gone through radical changes. First, he was able to fashion an armor of densely packed snow around his human form when lowering his temperature; later, this became armor of solid ice. Eventually, he was actually able to transform his body into organic ice in which his strength and endurance were augmented to enhanced levels, but when he turned his body back to normal, he would be an ordinary human.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Iceman">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/Iceman.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iceman_%28comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Gambit|Phoenix|Professor X|Psylocke|Rogue|Wolverine</allies>		<enemies>Apocalypse|Galactus|Juggernaut|Magneto|Mystique</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="altered" date="1961" gender="female" morality="hero" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Invisible Woman</name>      <identity>Susan Richards</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee and Jack Kirby</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Invisibility, lygokinetic force-field generation.</powers>      <weakness>Limited force-field strength.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The Invisible Woman formerly the Invisible Girl (alias changed in <em>Fantastic Four #284</em>), is a fictional superhero, who is a member of The Fantastic Four in the Marvel Comics universe. She was created by Stan Lee and Jack Kirby, in <em>The Fantastic Four (Vol. 1) #1</em> (Nov. 1961).<br /><br /><a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Mister Incredible">Reed Richards</a>, working in the field of Aerospace engineering, was designing a spacecraft for interstellar travel. Everything was going well until the government stopped funding of his project. Richards, wanting to see his project through, decided to make an unscheduled test flight. Originally, it was only going to be Reed and his best friend, <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Thing">Ben Grimm</a>, involved, but Susan was instrumental in persuading Reed in letting her brother and herself join them on the dangerous space mission. In space, the quartet was exposed to massive amounts of cosmic radiation. As a result, they had to abort the mission and return to Earth. After the crash landing, they realized that they gained superhuman powers.<br /><br />Realizing the potential use of their abilities, the four of them became the Fantastic Four, for the benefit of mankind. As the Fantastic Four, the team found themselves setting up their first headquarters in the Baxter Building in Manhattan. The Fantastic Four encountered many villains in the early part of their career, but none of them contended for Susan's affections more than <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Namor">Namor</a> the Sub-Mariner. Sue felt an amount of attraction to Namor, but her heart belonged with Reed.<br /><br />Sue developed the ability to generate a form of energy native to hyperspace. At first, she could only use this form of energy to bend light waves at her command, generating a tightly knit field of energy around herself to render her body and clothing invisible to the naked eye. Sue's vision has also adapted to this ability, extending partially into the cosmic spectrum so she could still see objects cloaked by this energy. After some training, she eventually developed the ability to project this energy outwards to render other objects invisible. As a side effect, Sue also discovered that she could send her invisible energy in waves and sweeps to disrupt other invisibility effects, rendering them visible.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Invisible_Woman">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/InvisibleWoman.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invisible_Woman">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Captain America|Hulk|Human Torch|Iron Man|Mister Fantastic|Spider-Man|Thing|Thor|Wolverine</allies>		<enemies>Doctor Doom|Galactus</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1963" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Iron Man</name>      <identity>Anthony Stark</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee, Larry Lieber, Don Heck, and Jack Kirby</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Genius-level intellect, wears suits of powered armor which endow him with superhuman abilities.</powers>      <weakness>Mechanical flaws, magnetic fields, electricity.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Iron Man (Tony Stark) is a superhero from Marvel Comics. He was created by Stan Lee, Larry Lieber, Don Heck and Jack Kirby in <em>Tales of Suspense #39</em> (March 1963).<br /><br />Stark entered the undergraduate electrical engineering program at MIT while only 15 years old and graduated at the top of his class. When he was 21, he inherited his father's company, Stark Industries, after his parents were killed in a car accident. One of the first things Stark did was to buy out the company that made the faulty brakes on his parent's car and correct the mechanical problem.<br /><br />While on a visit to Vietnam to see how his new mini-transistors could assist the American war effort, Tony Stark was caught in a booby trap. Captured by a Vietnamese warlord named Wong Chu, and dying from a piece of shrapnel lodged in his heart from the booby trap, Stark was pressed into building weapons for Wong Chu, along with a fellow prisoner, the famed physicist Yin Sen (later spelled Ho Yinsen). However, Stark and Yin Sen used the workshop to secretly design and construct a suit of powered armor - an iron exoskeleton that gave Stark tremendous strength as well as other abilities - that would not only keep Stark's heart beating, but also allow him to escape. Yin Sen sacrificed himself to buy Stark time to charge the bulky suit of armor, and as Iron Man, Stark made short work of Wong Chu and his men.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Iron_Man_%28Anthony_Stark%29">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/IronManI.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iron_Man">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Captain America|Daredevil|Elektra|Hulk|Invisible Woman|Spider-Man|Thor|Wolverine</allies>		<enemies>Doctor Doom</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1940" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Missing">		<name>Joker</name>      <identity>Unknown</identity>      <creator>Bill Finger and Jerry Robinson</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>Fiendish intelligence, particularly in the field of chemistry, some skill in hand to hand combat.</powers>      <weakness>Insanity, obsession with Batman.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The Joker is a fictional DC Comics villain, widely considered to be <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Batman">Batman</a>'s arch-enemy and the most well-known villain in comic book history. The idea was conceived by Batman inker\letterer Jerry Robinson (while on staff under Batman creator\artist Bob Kane), the Joker first appeared in <em>Batman #1</em> (1940). Originally conceived as an evil "court-jester" type, the character was rejected by studio writer Bill Finger as being "too clownish" however, he later relayed the idea to Bob Kane. Kane, who started out as a "gag" artist, loved the concept and encouraged its production. Mr. Finger found a photograph of actor Conrad Veidt wearing make-up for a silent film entitled The Man Who Laughs (which was based on a novel by Victor Hugo) and it was from this photograph that the Joker was modelled.<br /><br />The Joker is a humor-obsessed criminal with a clown-like appearance, who likes to kill people with fatal hilarity. Writers have alternatively portrayed him as a goofy trickster-thief or as a serial killer with a warped sense of humor. The Joker commits crimes with countless "comedic" weapons (such as razor sharp playing cards, acid-spewing flowers, cyanide pies, and lethally electric joy buzzers) and Joker venom, a deadly poison that infects his victims with a ghoulish rictus grin as they die while laughing uncontrollably (although some versions cause immediate death, without the painful laugh spasms beforehand.) This venom comes in many forms, from gas to darts to liquid poison, and has been his primary calling card from 1940 till the present.<br /><br />Part of the Joker's prominence among Batman's enemies likely derives from the fact that he, more than any other villain, represents the antithesis of Batman's personality and methods. Batman is almost always depicted, even in the campy 1960s television show, as a serious, stoic man who pursues his campaign against crime with utter earnestness and a disciplined, focused mind. In the darker portrayals of the comics and more recent films and television, the Dark Knight is further depicted as a brooding and humorless avenger who pursues justice as an enigmatic shadow striking from the dead of night. The Joker, by contrast, is literally a killer clown, driven by a disordered mind to pursue destruction and chaos with as much panache as possible. His appearance and actions suggest the bright and garish pomp and circumstance of the circus. <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Nightwing">Nightwing</a> has stated that he believes the Joker and Batman exist because of each other, that Batman represents order and Joker the chaos that challenges it. Like <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Superman">Superman</a> and <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Lex Luthor">Lex Luthor</a>, it has been suggested that Batman and the Joker need each other.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/secret_files/pdfs/joker.pdf">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/dc/Joker.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joker_%28comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Ocean Master|Penguin|Shadow-Thief</allies>		<enemies>Batman|Black Canary|Nightwing|Oracle|Superman</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1965" gender="male" morality="antihero" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Juggernaut</name>      <identity>Cain Marko</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee and Jack Kirby</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Resistance to being stopped, super-strength, invulnerability.</powers>      <weakness>Vulnerable to mental manipulation when not wearing his helmet.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Juggernaut (Cain Marko) is a fictional character in Marvel Comics' universe, a former supervillain and current superhero. He was created by Stan Lee and Jack Kirby in <em>X-Men (volume 1) #12</em> (July 1965).<br /><br />Cain Marko is the step-brother of <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Professor X">Charles Xavier</a>, founder of the X-Men. His father, Kurt Marko, married Charles' mother, Sharon, after her husband Brian Xavier died. Kurt neglected Cain and drove Sharon to alcoholism. Anti-social and malicious in general, Cain held a special contempt for his step-brother Charles Xavier who due to a hidden mutant power of telepathy excelled at all endeavors and cast Cain completely in shadow. One day Cain was further humiliated as Xavier accidentally probed his mind and learned of Cain's insecurities toward him. The revelation to Cain that Xavier's success that loomed over him was actually gained through a secret superhuman advantage intensified Cain's resentment toward Xavier considerably.<br /><br />Because of his association with the X-Men, Juggernaut is often mistakenly labeled a mutant. Juggernaut traditionally possessed huge power, of mystical origin. He had tremendous physical strength, a total resistance to physical injury due to his mystic spell of invulnerability; an impenetrable force field that he could summon at will; and unlimited stamina. His spell also granted him unbreakable skin, therefore making his forcefield an added protection in case he did not wish for a certain attack to touch his physical body. Due to the mystical energies flowing through his body, he did not need to eat, breathe, or drink fluids. As a vessel of mystic energy, he also possessed many abstract powers that had yet to be fully revealed. Finally, while moving, he could, essentially, not be stopped. To compensate for his most significant vulnerability; to telepathic assault - he also wore a helmet of a mystical alloy, which prevented his mind from being read or attacked.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Juggernaut_%28Cain_Marko%29">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/marvel/Juggernaut.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Juggernaut_%28comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Gambit|Iceman|Phoenix|Iceman|Psylocke|Spider-Man|Wolverine</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1967" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Jailed">		<name>Kingpin</name>      <identity>Wilson Fisk</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee and John Romita Sr.</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Highly intelligent, extremely strong and agile as a hand to hand combatant.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The Kingpin (Wilson Fisk) is a supervillain in Marvel Comics' universe who is an enemy of <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Spider-Man">Spider-Man</a>, <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Daredevil">Daredevil</a>, and the <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Punisher">Punisher</a>. He was created by Stan Lee and John Romita Sr., first appearing in <em>Amazing Spider-Man #50</em>.<br /><br />Wilson Fisk is a criminal mastermind who is involved in extensive illegal activities such as drug running, smuggling, murder, and so forth. Despite this, he has no criminal record and an army of lawyers to keep it that way, and is a criminal financial strategist without parallel. Fisk has no superhuman powers, but the majority of his 400-plus pound bulk is muscle (when he delivered a kick to the Kingpin's back, Daredevil could only think, "Whatever that was, it wasn't fat. Felt more like rock"). He is a superb fighter who has held his own against Spider-Man, but in recent years Daredevil has occupied his attention. He has been aware of Daredevil's secret identity for years, thanks to Karen Page's indiscretion. Though Spider-Man and Daredevil are his greatest enemies, he has also tangled with <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Captain America">Captain America</a>, Moon Knight, <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Doctor Strange">Doctor Strange</a>, The Punisher, the Avengers, and <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Ghost Rider">Ghost Rider</a>, among others. He has employed any number of costumed criminals and assassins, notably <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Elektra">Elektra</a>, <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Bullseye">Bullseye</a>, Jack O'Lantern, and Typhoid Mary.<br /><br />The Kingpin has no superhuman powers. However, he is as strong and durable as it is possible for a man of his height, weight, and build who engages in intensive regular exercise to be, and he is a very large man (over six and a half feet tall). Like Captain America, Fisk is stronger than any Olympic athlete who has ever competed. His stamina is likewise honed to the virtual pinnacle of human abilility. He has remarkable agility and dexterity for a man of his size.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Kingpin">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/marvel/Kingpin.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kingpin_%28comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Captain America|Daredevil|Elektra|Punisher|Red Skull|Spider-Man</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1940" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Lex Luthor</name>      <identity>Alexander Joseph "Lex" Luthor</identity>      <creator>Jerry Siegel and Joe Shuster</creator>      <company>Comics Magazine Company (now DC Comics)</company>      <powers>None. However, posseses a brilliant scientific mind and strong Machiavellian skills, and is a billionare with access to several resources, political power.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal, obsession with Superman.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The (usually) bald-headed Luthor has been <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Superman">Superman</a>'s main foe for most of the superhero's existence and has unveiled countless plots to destroy him and take over the world. Originally Luthor was a mad scientist but has since been rewritten as a Machiavellian industrialist and white-collar criminal. For a brief period in the early 2000s, he was president of the United States.<br /><br />Luthor is one of several Superman characters with the initials "LL," including Lois Lane, Lana Lang, Lionel Luthor, Letitia Lerner, Lori Lemaris, and Linda Lee (aka Supergirl).<br /><br />When Luthor first appeared, he was portrayed with a full head of red hair; however, in 1941 Luthor came to be portrayed as completely bald after an artist's mistake in the Superman comic strip. Shuster preferred drawing bald villains anyway, so the more striking appearance was adopted and became a Luthor trademark. The change may also have been an attempt to echo a previous villain, the Ultra-Humanite, with whom Luthor shares many similarities. When the DC multiverse began to take hold in the 1960s, the red-haired Luthor was said to be the bald Luthor's Earth-Two counterpart, Alexei Luthor.<br /><br />Luthor's originally stated goals were to kill Superman and to take over Earth as a stepping stone to dominating the universe. Over the years, Luthor came up with every conceivable plan to destroy Superman: he has synthesized kryptonite; traveled back in time; summoned beings from the fourth dimension; created robots, clones, and genetic monstrosities; allied himself with the alien super-computer android <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Brainiac">Brainiac</a>; animated kryptonite rocks; detonated H-bombs; and has masqueraded and taken on a number of aliases. Although none of his schemes worked permanently (though one classic non-canonical "imaginary story" from the 1960s called <em>The Death of Superman</em> has Luthor finally killing Superman with Kryptonite after lulling him by pretending to go straight), Luthor's persistence has made him Superman's most troublesome foe.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/secret_files/pdfs/lex_luthor.pdf">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/dc/LexLuthor.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lex_Luthor">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Joker|Ocean Master|Penguin|Shadow-Thief</allies>		<enemies>Batman|Superman</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="alien" date="1983" gender="male" morality="antihero" era="Bronze" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Lobo</name>      <identity>Lobo</identity>      <creator>Keith Giffen and Roger Slifer</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>Super-strength and durability, can survive in space unaided, increased sense of smell, accelerated healing, self-replication when wounded, immortal, art of exploding numbers.</powers>      <weakness>Strict personal code of honor, extremely protective of space dolphins.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Lobo is a DC Comics antihero, arguably a superhero. Created by artist Keith Giffen and writer Roger Slifer, he first appeared in <em>Omega Men #3</em> (1983).<br /><br />An alien from the planet Czarnia who works as an intergalactic mercenary, Lobo was intended to be an over-the-top parody of 1980s-era Marvel Comics antiheroes. Lobo has the dress and attitude of a caricatured version of the Hells Angels and has an extreme love of bloodshed and destruction. He has been featured in a number of comic books noteworthy for their ironic portrayals of over-the-top violence. Although meant as a one-note gag, Lobo was one of DC's most popular new characters in the 1990s.<br /><br />Lobo is a Czarnian, possessing exceptional strength and fortitude. He enjoys nothing better than mindless violence and intoxication. Killing is an end in itself: his name is Khundian for "he who devours your entrails and thoroughly enjoys it". He is also arrogant and self-centered, focusing almost solely on his own pleasures, although he proudly lives up to his word. Lobo is the last of his kind, having killed all the other Czarnians. Possibly, Lobo cannot stay dead, as both Heaven and Hell threw him out.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/secret_files/pdfs/lobo.pdf">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.spider-bob.com/heroes/dc/Lobo.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lobo_(DC_Comics)">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Superman|Wolverine</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="mutant" date="1963" gender="male" morality="antihero" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Retired">		<name>Magneto</name>      <identity>Erik Magnus Lehnsherr</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee and Jack Kirby</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Magnetokinesis allowing flight and control of the whole electromagnetic spectrum, skilled inventor and strategist.</powers>      <weakness>Vulnerable to mental manipulation when not wearing his helmet, cannot effect non-metal objects.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Magneto (alias Erik Magnus Lehnsherr) is a mutant in the Marvel Comics universe. He has at various times been a supervillain, a superhero, and an anti-hero and in his role as a villain - arguably his most famous role, though not his most complex - he is the primary antagonist of the X-Men. He was created by Stan Lee and Jack Kirby, though it was writer Chris Claremont who would later flesh out and develop the character into the one he is today.<br /><br />Magneto is a survivor of the Auschwitz death camp. As a young boy with his power over magnetism not yet developed, he and his family were persecuted for being Jewish. Magneto witnessed the murder of his family by the Nazis during the Holocaust. He alone survived and was sent into the camps being forced by the Nazis to work in the Sonderkommandos. Magneto has since been tormented by the fact that he could have put a stop to the entire process had he only been aware of his full powers at the time.<br /><br />Arguably the most powerful man on the planet, Magneto is a mutant with the superhuman power of magnetokinesis. He can shape and manipulate magnetic fields that exist naturally or artificially. Magneto can thus lift, move, and manipulate objects (sometimes weighing many thousands of tons), and manipulate bloodflow to others' brains to cause aneurysms or unconsciousness. He can absorb and redirect electricity, control ferrous particles in the atmosphere, even the very air, alter the Earth's magnetic field which extends into space as the Magnetosphere, increase his own strength to the extent of being able to exchange blows with at least Colossus, fly in or beyond the Earth's atmosphere, and achieve an indefinite range of other effects.<br /><br />Just as <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Professor X">Professor X</a> was inspired by Martin Luther King, Jr., it is possible that Magneto could have been inspired by Malcolm X.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Magneto">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/marvel/Magneto.htm">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magneto_%28comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Mystique</allies>		<enemies>Gambit|Iceman|Phoenix|Professor X|Psylocke|Wolverine</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="alien" date="1955" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Martian Manhunter</name>      <identity>J'onn J'onzz</identity>      <creator>Joseph Samachson</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>Flight, invulnerability, super-strength, speed, telepathy, invisibility, intangibility, shape-shifting, "Martian vision" (a form of eye beam that uses visible psychokinetic force).</powers>      <weakness>Fire, Oreos.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The Martian Manhunter (J'onn J'onzz), alternately known as the Manhunter from Mars, is a comic book superhero appearing in DC Comics. He first appeared in a back-up story in <em>Detective Comics #225</em> (cover date: November, 1955), written by Joseph Samachson and illustrated by Joe Certa. His first appearance is often considered the beginning of the superhero resurgence known as the Silver Age of comic books.<br /><br />J'onzz is a native of the planet Mars and possesses abilities similar to those of <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Superman">Superman</a>, but is additionally endowed with the powers of invisibilty, telepathy and the ability to change shape. His usual appearance is of a tall, hairless, green-skinned humanoid with a pronounced brow. He is highly sensitive to fire; in some stories this weakness is a physical weakness, and in others it is psychological. A recent story in the JLA comic book indicates that the Guardians of the Universe instilled the aversion to fire into the Martians to prevent them from overrunning the universe. This weakness has been addressed in recent times.<br /><br />In his debut story, J'onn J'onzz was accidentally teleported to Earth by a human scientist, Dr. Erdel, who immediately had a heart attack and died, leaving the Martian stranded and unable to return through the so-called "Erdel Gate" through which he had been teleported. Fortunately, he was able to use his powers to fit in; adopting a human-like appearance and calling himself "John Jones", he joined the police force, secretly using his alien powers to help the inhabitants of his new home planet.<br /><br />He has an odd addiction to Oreo cookies.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/secret_files/pdfs/martian_manhunter.pdf">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/dc/MartianManhunter.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Martian_Manhunter">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Aquaman|Batman|Black Canary|Flash|Green Arrow|Green Lantern|Hawkman|Plastic Man|Superman|Wonder Woman</allies>		<enemies>Darkseid</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="altered" date="1961" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Mister Fantastic</name>      <identity>Reed Richards</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee and Jack Kirby</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Superhuman intelligence, durability, extreme malleability.</powers>      <weakness>Energy weapons, taffy-pullers, magic, temporary power loss.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Mister Fantastic (Reed Richards) is a Marvel Comics superhero who is the leader of the Fantastic Four. He has the ability to manipulate his body by stretching and shaping it to any shape he desires. As scientist and inventor Reed Richards, he is widely acknowledged as a super-genius and one of the most intelligent people on Earth.<br /><br />Reed Richards' powers are those of elasticity itself. He has complete mental control of seemingly every molecule in his body. He has been observed as being able to utilize his stretching form in a variety of offensive and defensive manners, such as compressing himself into a ball and ricocheting into enemies or flattening himself into a trampoline or a parachute to rescue a teammate. He can twist or reshape his body or stretch roughly three miles, and as thin as a single molecule. He can flatten himself to the thickness of a sheet of vellum.<br /><br />Because of his elastic nature, Mr. Fantastic cannot be harmed by bullets or other projectile weapons, including knives, missiles, darts, etc, and all projectiles rebound to the attacker. Despite this, Reed is not invulnerable to harm. Though rare and extremely difficult to do, Reed's skin has been cut at least once, by an evolved form of a Brood queen (or possibly an as of yet unnamed alien race). He has also occasionally demonstrated other applications of this molecular control. While imprisoned by Psycho-Man, he willfully reduced his body to a nearly liquid state in order to flow out of a glass encasement specially prepared by the villain to have only the most infinitesimal of openings.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Mister_Fantastic">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/MrFantastic.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mister_Fantastic">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Captain America|Human Torch|Invisible Woman|Spider-Man|Thing|Thor|Wolverine</allies>		<enemies>Doctor Doom|Galactus</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="alien" date="1944" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Mister Mxyzptlk</name>      <identity>Mxyzptlk</identity>      <creator>Jerry Siegel and Joe Shuster</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>Not bound by third-dimensional laws, can perform nearly any feat using what either is or appears to be magic.</powers>      <weakness>Can not stand being ridiculed, if he said or spelled his name backwards he was involuntarily sent back to his home dimension for a minimum of 90 days.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Mister Mxyzptlk (roughly pronounced Mix-yez-pit-lick, also nicknamed Mxy) is a fictional supervillain who appears in DC Comics' <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Superman">Superman</a> comic books. He was created by Jerry Siegel and first appeared in <em>Superman (volume 1) #30</em> (September 1944).<br /><br />Originally, Mxyzptlk had designs on conquering the planet for himself, but soon settled for tormenting Superman whenever he got the opportunity. His only weaknesses were that he could not stand being ridiculed and if he said or spelled his name backwards, Kltpzyxm (pronounced kil-tip-zee-zim), he was involuntarily sent back to his home dimension for a minimum of 90 days. Mxyzptlk would often look for ways to counter the latter weakness, but he always proved gullible enough for Superman to trick him time and time again.<br /><br />Mxyztplk appeared originally as a small bald man in a purple suit, green bow tie and purple derby hat. This was changed to a futuristic looking orange outfit with purple trim in the mid-1950s, although the hat remained. At around this time the spelling of Mxyzptlk's name changed (by mistake) to "Mxyzptlk".</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.spider-bob.com/villains/dc/Mxyzptlk.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mr._Mxyzptlk">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Superman</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="mutant" date="1978" gender="female" morality="antihero" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Mystique</name>      <identity>Raven Darkholme</identity>      <creator>Chris Claremont and Dave Cockrum</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Metamorphic shapeshifter able to adapt any humanoid form or genetic trait (except superhuman abilities), heal surface tissue damage, withstand all pathogens and poisons, and suppress her natural aging.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Mystique (Raven Darkholme) is a fictional character, a comic book supervillain in the Marvel Comics universe. She has run several incarnations of the Brotherhood of Evil Mutants, but is currently a member of the X-Men.<br /><br />Mystique's exact age remains unknown. However her earliest meeting with her friend Destiny (Irene Adler) is stated to have occurred at "the dawn of the 20th century." Because a Sherlock Holmes character named Irene Adler from the same time period is romantically linked to Holmes, this can be interpreted to mean either that she was Holmes or that Holmes' apparent death in The Adventure of the Final Problem was real and that she replaced him afterwards; however, no comics story has yet confirmed this.<br /><br />Mystique is a mutant, a shapeshifter able to alter the formation of her biological cells at will and thereby assume the form of other humans. Originally, it was clearly stated that Mystique's powers were limited to appearances only, as she could not assume the powers of the people she morphed into or alter her body to adapt to different situations. In addition, she could not change her overall body mass, and change into a person larger or smaller than she is.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Mystique">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/marvel/Mystique.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mystique_%28comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Magneto</allies>		<enemies>Gambit|Iceman|Phoenix|Professor X|Psylocke|Wolverine</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1939" gender="male" morality="antihero" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Namor</name>      <identity>Namor McKenzie</identity>      <creator>Bill Everett</creator>      <company>Quality Comics (now DC Comics)</company>      <powers>Fully amphibious physiognomy and suited for high water pressure, super strength, high speed swimming, atmospheric flight, command of marine life, limited ability to absorb and project electric energy, ability to mimic physical traits of sea creatures.</powers>      <weakness>Weakened powers out-of-water.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Namor the Sub-Mariner is a fictional character featured in Marvel Comics, and one of the oldest superhero characters. He was created by cartoonist Bill Everett in 1939.<br /><br />Like the subsequent DC Comics' character <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Aquaman">Aquaman</a>, Namor is an undersea hero originating from the mythical kingdom of Atlantis. Namor is the son of a human sea captain and a princess of Atlantis (although the Underwater kingdom was left unnamed until the 1960s). Possessing the super-strength and aquatic abilities of the "Homo mermanus" race, Namor was alternatively portrayed as: a good-natured but short-fused superhero; and, a hostile invader, seeking vengeance for perceived wrongs that misguided surface-dwellers committed against his undersea kingdom. He was thus arguably the first comic book anti-hero.<br /><br />Everett's unique early anti-hero would, in time, go up against Carl Burgos' android superhero, the Human Torch, yet eventually, as the US entered the Second World War, ally himself with the Torch and the human race against Adolf Hitler and the Axis Powers.<br /><br />In the 1960's he primarily allied himself with <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Doctor Doom">Doctor Doom</a> against the Fantastic Four - despite feeling a very strong attraction to the <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Invisible Woman">Invisible Woman</a>, so strong in fact that he fought to win her heart from her lover <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Mister Fantastic">Mister Fantastic</a>.<br /><br />Namor has remained a constant for Atlas (now Marvel) Comics. Never really a hero or villain, he has protected his kingdom and sought vengeance on the surface world only when he feels his realm is threatened. Although he has served alongside, or even as a member of, several superhero teams - most notably The Defenders and The Avengers - he remains an outsider.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Namor">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Invisible Woman</allies>		<enemies>Doctor Doom|Mister Fantastic</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1984" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Bronze" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Nightwing</name>      <identity>Richard John "Dick" Grayson</identity>      <creator>Marv Wolfman and George Perez</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>No super-human powers, peak human level athlete/acrobat, exceptional martial artist, strategist and leader, master detective, access to hi-tech gadgets and weapons.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Richard John "Dick" Grayson is a superhero in the DC Comics Universe. He is Bruce Wayne's first ward (later on adopted son), and the original crimefighter to create the secret identity of Robin, the Boy Wonder, before evolving into the superhero Nightwing.<br /><br />The character of Dick Grayson was created by Bob Kane, Bill Finger and Jerry Robinson in 1940, while the Nightwing persona was created by Marv Wolfman and George Perez in 1984.<br /><br />In Pre-Crisis on Infinite Earths continuity, the maturing Dick Grayson grew weary of his role as Batman's young sidekick. He renamed himself Nightwing, recalling his adventure on the Kryptonian city of Kandor, where he and <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Batman">Batman</a> met the local hero of the same name.<br /><br />Asked what Dick should be, if he could not be Robin, <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Superman">Superman</a> told a tale of long ago on Krypton, about a man who was cast out of his family, just like Dick had been. He dreamed of a world ruled by justice, and set out to protect the helpless. His true identity was never revealed; he was known only as Nightwing. Dick then decided to honor the legendary Kryptonian by renaming himself Nightwing.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/secret_files/pdfs/nightwing.pdf">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.spider-bob.com/heroes/dc/NightwingIII.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dick_Grayson">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Batman|Raven</allies>		<enemies>Bane|Catwoman|Joker|Penguin|Ra's al Ghul</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1966" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Silver" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Ocean Master</name>      <identity>Orm Marius</identity>      <creator>Bob Haney and Nick Cardy</creator>      <company>Quality Comics (now DC Comics)</company>      <powers>None. Uses a magical trident and high tech equipment.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The Ocean Master is a DC Comics supervillain, and one of <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Aquaman">Aquaman</a>'s greatest enemies. He first appeared in <em>Aquaman #29</em> (September-October 1966).<br /><br />Initially, he was a high-tech pirate who attacked ships, before using a whale to cause natural disasters and hold the world to ransom. Aquaman and Aqualad were captured by Ocean Master, but managed to escape. Aquaman was then unable to fight Ocean Master, although he does stop his plan. At the end of the story he told Aqualad that, when he saw Ocean Master without his mask he realised the villain was his half-brother, Orm Curry. Orm was the son of Tom Curry and a human woman, and therefore had none of Aquaman's powers. He was already on his way to becoming a criminal when he came down with amnesia, and now has no recollection of his former life.<br /><br />In his subsequent appearances Ocean Master, believing Aquaman was afraid of him, had decided to overthrow Aquaman and usurp his throne. Unable to survive underwater, he made special costume and helmet to help him breathe while in the ocean and clashed with Aquaman many times. He eventually regained his memory, but continued to plot against his brother.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/dc/OceanMaster.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ocean_Master">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Joker|Lex Luthor|Shadow-Thief</allies>		<enemies>Aquaman</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1989" gender="female" morality="hero" era="Bronze" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Oracle</name>      <identity>Barbara Gordon</identity>      <creator>Gardner Fox and Carmine Infantino</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>No super-human powers, genius-level intellect, superb hacker, skilled detective and martial artist.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal, paralyzed.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Barbara Gordon is a fictional character appearing in DC Comics and related media. From 1967 to 1988 she was the superhero known as Batgirl; since 1988 she has been known as Oracle.<br /><br />The librarian-by-day Barbara Gordon made her debut in 1967 in <em>Detective Comics #359</em> as the daughter of Gotham City's Police Commissioner James Gordon. On her way to a masquerade ball dressed as a female version of <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Batman">Batman</a>, Barbara intervened in a kidnapping attempt on Bruce Wayne by the villainous Killer Moth, attracting the attention of Batman and leading to a crime-fighting career.<br /><br />In <em>The Killing Joke</em>, a graphic novel by Alan Moore and Brian Bolland, the <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Joker">Joker</a>, as part of his plan to drive James Gordon into madness due to "one bad day", shot Barbara through the spine, paralyzing her, and ending her career as Batgirl forever.<br /><br />Drawing on her genius-level intellect, photographic memory, her vast knowledge of computers and electronics, her expert skills as a hacker, and her training as a librarian, Barbara adopted the codename Oracle. She now acts as an information broker, gathering and disseminating intelligence to law-enforcement organizations and members of the superhero community. She has also trained herself under the tutelege of Richard Dragon to engage in combat from her wheelchair should the need for it arise.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/secret_files/pdfs/oracle.pdf">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.spider-bob.com/heroes/dc/Oracle.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oracle_(comics)">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Batman|Catwoman|Nightwing</allies>		<enemies>Joker|Penguin</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="alien" date="1994" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Bronze" owner="DC" currently="Jailed">		<name>Parallax</name>      <identity>Parallax</identity>      <creator>Martin Nodell and Bill Finger</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>Flight, possession, fear induction.</powers>      <weakness>Green.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Parallax is a fictional comic book villain from DC Comics. Created by writer Geoff Johns and artist Ethan Van Sciver, Parallax's true form was first seen in the miniseries <em>Green Lantern: Rebirth #3</em> (February 2005), but was built upon pre-existing material by writer Ron Marz that Marz had established in <em>Green Lantern #48</em> (January 1994), such as the character's name.<br /><br />Parallax, which appears to be a yellow spindly creature with thin limbs, a snake-like tail, insect-like wings, and a monstrous, gaping mouth lined with teeth when manifesting himself in a form visible to humans, is an extraterrestrial parasitic entity that feeds on fear. The extraterrestrial samaritans known as the Guardians of the Universe imprisoned Parallax on the planet Oa, in the <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Green Lantern">Green Lantern</a> Main Battery, the energy source for the power rings wielded by the Guardians' agents, the intergalactic police force known as the Green Lantern Corps. The imprisonment of Parallax in the Battery weakens the ring bearers' control over the yellow portion of the spectrum, which is why Green Lanterns' rings have historically been unable to affect anything of that color, a liability that has been mitigated in recent years.<br /><br />Parallax was actually an ancient demonic parasitic entity dating back to the dawn of time, that actually was the sentient embodiment of fear, and which traveled from world to world, feeding off the fear of sentient beings, and causing entire civilizations to destroy themselves out of paranoia.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/dc/Parallax.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parallax_%28comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Green Lantern</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>		    <character origin="human" date="1941" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Penguin</name>      <identity>Oswald Chesterfield Cobblepot</identity>      <creator>Bill Finger</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>Assorted "trick" umbrellas, usage of birds in crimes.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal, overly status-concerned.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The Penguin, real name Oswald Chesterfield Cobblepot, a fictional character, is a DC Comics supervillain and an enemy of <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Batman">Batman</a>. Created by Bill Finger (although Bob Kane is credited by DC Comics), he first appeared in <em>Detective Comics #58</em> (1941).<br /><br />Born Oswald Cobblepot, the Penguin was teased very much in childhood due to his short stature, obesity, and bird-like nose. These traits made him an outcast in his rich, debutante family. Their rejection drove him to become a violent criminal.<br /><br />A short, chubby man who usually wears a tuxedo and a top hat, the Penguin fancies himself a "gentleman of crime". Unlike most Batman villains, the Penguin does not theme his crimes around a psychotic obsession, but does possess a few eccentricities. He is known for his love of birds and his umbrellas, which allow him to glide through the air, double as firearms or have some other specialized function. He also typically keeps beautiful women around him; there have been suggestions in some comics that he does so to remind others of his monetary influence and to compensate for his own grotesqueness.<br /><br />He is seen as a mobster type criminal, more intelligent like The Riddler, both of whom seem to be above the usual murderous rogue gallery. To that end, the Penguin's gentleman-villain personality makes him a stark contrast or foil to the more manic and demented villains, most notably the <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Joker">Joker</a>.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/dc/Penguin.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Penguin">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Darkseid|Lex Luthor|Shadow-Thief</allies>		<enemies>Batman</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="altered" date="1941" gender="female" morality="hero" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Deceased">		<name>Phantom Lady</name>      <identity>Sandra Knight</identity>      <creator>Jack Cole</creator>      <company>Quality Comics (now DC Comics)</company>      <powers>None.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Phantom Lady is one of the first female superhero characters, debuting in the 1940s Golden Age of comic books. Originally published by Quality Comics, she is presently part of the DC Comics universe after having been published by a series of now-defunct comic book companies in the interim.<br /><br />As published by Fox Feature Syndicate in the late 1940s, the busty and scantily-clad Phantom Lady is a notable and controversial example of "good girl art", a style of comic art depicting voluptuous female characters in provocative situations and pin-up poses that contributed to widespread criticism of the medium's effect on children.<br /><br />Phantom Lady first appeared in Quality's <em>Police Comics #1</em> (August, 1941), an anthology title which also marked the debut of other characters such as Plastic Man and the Human Bomb. After finding a "black light ray projector" that a family friend named Professor Davis sent to her father, she adopted the device as a weapon that could blind her enemies, or turn herself invisible if she aimed it at herself.<br /><br />She assumed the identity of Phantom Lady in a costume that consisted of a green cape and the equivalent of a one-piece yellow swimsuit. Stories published decades later by DC Comics after it acquired the character would alter details of this origin, giving her a more active and aggressive role in her own empowerment, and explaining her skimpy costume as a deliberate tactic to distract her usually male foes.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/dc/PhantomLady.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br />><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phantom_Lady">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies></enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>		<character origin="mutant" date="1986" gender="female" morality="nblurred" era="Bronze" owner="Marvel" currently="Retired">		<name>Phoenix</name>      <identity>Jean Grey</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee and Jack Kirby</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Telepathy, telekinesis, Phoenix Force.</powers>      <weakness>Jean Grey's emotional states.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Phoenix (Jean Grey) is a comic book superhero in the Marvel Comics universe. Early during her career she used the code name Marvel Girl and was a founding member of the X-Men (and remained a vital member of the team). Created by Stan Lee and Jack Kirby, she first appeared in <em>X-Men #1</em> (1963).<br /><br />Jean's Phoenix Force powers manifested later and significantly boosted her mental abilities allowing her to rearrange matter at a subatomic level, to fly un-aided through space, create intense heat and thermal energy by stimulating molecular activity, manipulate the voluntary and involuntary responses in the human body. She manifested a "telekinetic sensitivity"; that let her feel the texture of objects she had a telekinetic hold on, feel when other objects came into contact with them and probe them at a molecular level to identify alien materials or feel when two things she "held" were similarly composed. In addition to this, when the power of the Phoenix force is engaged, she is surrounded in a flame-like energy corona that takes the form of a large bird of fire.<br /><br />Later, Jean learned that not only was she the physical embodiment of the Phoenix Force, but she was the "White Phoenix of the Crown" and as such, had the power to control entire timelines and travel to other dimensions by creating portals between realities. Also, it was revealed that Phoenix's mind resonates across the multiverse, and may be a nexus of realities.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Phoenix_%28Jean_Grey%29">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/PhoenixII.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jean_Grey">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Iceman|Psylocke|Wolverine</allies>		<enemies>Apocalypse|Juggernaut|Magneto|Mystique</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="altered" date="1941" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Plastic Man</name>      <identity>Patrick O'Brian</identity>      <creator>Jack Cole</creator>      <company>Quality Comics (now DC Comics)</company>      <powers>Can stretch and shape his highly resilient body into any shape he can imagine, immune to telepathy, possible immortality.</powers>      <weakness>Cold.</weakness>	  <copy><p>One of the trademark characters of Quality Comics during the golden age, Plastic Man possesses the ability to stretch his body into any imaginable form. His adventures were known for their quirky, offbeat structure and surreal, slapstick humor. When Quality Comics shutdown in 1956, DC Comics acquired much of their stable of characters, including Plastic Man.<br /><br />Although never a commercial giant, Plastic Man has been a favorite character of many modern comic book creators, including writer Grant Morrison, who included him in his 1990s revival of the Justice League, and painter Alex Ross.<br /><br />Plastic Man had been a crook named Patrick "Eel" O'Brian when he was shot by a security guard and struck by a falling drum full of an unidentified acid, some of which entered Eel's wound. He was saved by a mysterious order of monks whose example cured his penchant for crime. The acid bath gave him the ability to change his shape. He wore dark glasses and a red-and-yellow costume as flexible as his body. Whatever shape he took, the colors remained the same, so there might be a red-and-yellow chandelier over a table full of plotting gangsters, or a red-and-yellow abstract painting hanging on the wall, but the villains never caught on until it was too late.<br /><br />A creation of Jack Cole, Plastic Man first appeared in <em>Police Comics #1</em> (Aug. 1941), an issue that also included the debuts of Phantom Lady and the Human Bomb, among others. Cole's offbeat humor, combined with Plastic Man's ability to take any shape, gave the cartoonist enormous opportunities to experiment with text and graphics in groundbreaking manner - helping to define the medium's visual vocabulary, and making the idiosyncratic character one of the few enduring classics from the Golden Age to modern times. His art was striking for its bright, cartoony quality, with Plastic Man stretching across panels, going around the corner and up the street, wisecracking all the way. Cole's stories were noted for good humor mixed with deadly, albeit slapstick, violence.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/secret_files/pdfs/plastic_man.pdf">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/dc/PlasticMan.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plastic_Man">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Aquaman|Batman|Black Canary|Flash|Green Arrow|Hawkman|Martian Manhunter|Superman|Wonder Woman</allies>		<enemies></enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="mutant" date="1963" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Retired">		<name>Professor X</name>      <identity>Charles Francis Xavier</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee and Jack Kirby</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Vast telepathic powers, easily able to read and project thoughts, and manipulate minds to alter memories, control minds, and cast illusions.</powers>      <weakness>Can be controlled by Brood, unable to penetrate Magneto's helmet.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Professor Charles Xavier, also known as Professor X, is a comic book character in the Marvel Comics universe. He is the founder, mentor and sometime leader of the team of mutant superheroes the X-Men. Created by Stan Lee and Jack Kirby, he first appeared in <em>X-Men (vol. 1) #1</em> (1963).<br /><br />Xavier is considered one of the most powerful mutants on Earth due to his psionic powers. Xavier can read, control and influence human minds and cast illusions. He can also detect the presence of other mutants. A natural genius, he is also a leading authority on genetics, mutation, and psionic powers, has considerable expertise in other life sciences and is highly talented in creating equipment for utilizing and enhancing psionic powers.<br /><br />A visionary, Xavier has devoted his life to helping mutants learn to live with their powers, and to helping mutants and normal humans coexist peacefully and without fear of one another.<br /><br />Professor Xavier's character is inspired by Martin Luther King, Jr. and St. Francis Xavier, and may also be a derivative of Marie Francois Xavier Bichat, or Charles Xavier from Vladimir Nabokov's 1962 book Pale Fire.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Professor_X">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/ProfessorX.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Professor_X">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Captain America|Iceman|Iron Man|Psylocke|Spider-Man|Thor|Wolverine</allies>		<enemies>Apocalypse|Galactus|Juggernaut|Hulk|Magneto|Mystique|Punisher</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="mutant" date="1976" gender="female" morality="hero" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Psylocke</name>      <identity>Elisabeth "Betsy" Braddock</identity>      <creator>Chris Claremont and Herb Trimpe</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Telekinesis, limited precognitive abilities, and able to direct mental energy as destructive mind blasts, psychic katanas.</powers>      <weakness>Limited in abilities.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Psylocke (real name Elisabeth Braddock) is a fictional character in the comic book X-Men and part of the Marvel Comics universe. Her first appearance was in <em>Captain Britain #8</em> (December 1976), a series only released in the U.K. Her first U.S. appearance was in <em>New Mutants Annual #2</em> (1986).<br /><br />Elisabeth (sometimes misspelled as Elizabeth) "Betsy" Braddock was born in and raised in England. Born in the small town of Maldon, Essex, Betsy and her brothers had a very privileged life. She is the twin sister of Brian Braddock, better known as the superhero Captain Britain and first appeared in his eponymous series. After working as a commercial pilot for some time, she dyed her hair purple, joined the psi-division of STRIKE (the British branch of the US-based espionage outfit S.H.I.E.L.D.), and went undercover as a fashion model.<br /><br />Psylocke was initially a telepath, and the use of her abilities often triggered the appearance of a butterfly-like mask of psionic energy on her face. She was capable of mentally communicating with and facilitating communication with others, altering a person's sensory perceptions (i.e. cast visual and auditory illusions), seeing and hearing through the minds of others, and projected devastating blasts (psychoblasts) of telepathic energy that could stun, cause a person to lose consciousness, and even die. Psylocke also had limited precognitive abilities. In her early days when she still had her original Caucasian body, she deployed traditional telepathic attacks in battles. She was not a skilled hand-to-hand combatant during this stage, so she relied on fighting from a distance using psi-blasts and similar tactics. Because of her physical vulnerability she was given body armour for a short while to off-set any physical attacks received.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Psylocke">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/Psylocke.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psylocke">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Iceman|Professor X|Wolverine</allies>		<enemies>Apocalypse|Juggernaut|Magneto|Mystique</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1974" gender="male" morality="antihero" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Punisher</name>      <identity>Al Simmons</identity>      <creator>Gerry Conway, Ross Andru, and John Romita Sr.</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>No superhuman powers. Highly trained armed and unarmed combatant, being proficient with hundreds of weapons. Expert with demolitions, has an extremely high threshold for pain, and is a remarkably resourceful tactical expert.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The Punisher (Frank Castle) is a Marvel Comics anti-hero. Created by Gerry Conway, he first appeared in <em>The Amazing Spider-Man #129</em> (1974).<br /><br />Although sometimes considered a hero, the Punisher is a savage and ruthless vigilante who considers killing and torture acceptable crime-fighting tactics. Driven by the murder of his family, Castle wages a one-man war on organized crime using all manner of weaponry. The Punisher is a master of close combat and a skilled marksman. Easily recognizable by the white skull icon on his chest, the Punisher is feared by all criminals.<br /><br />The Punisher's brutal nature and willingness to kill made him a novel character in mainstream American comic books in 1974. By the late 1980s, he was part of a wave of psychologically troubled anti-heroes and was featured in several monthly series.<br /><br />The Punisher can be seen as the revenge genre taken to an extreme as he not only takes his vengeance on the criminals who killed his family but all criminals nonstop. There is no final villain as is the case with many revenge sagas, the Punisher's war with crime continues without end.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Punisher">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/Punisher.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Punisher">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Daredevil</allies>		<enemies>Captain America|Elektra|Kingpin|Spider-Man|Wolverine</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1971" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Silver" owner="DC" currently="Deceased">		<name>Ra's al Ghul</name>      <identity>Ra's al Ghul</identity>      <creator>Dennis O'Neil and Neal Adams</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>Is a genius, an alchemist, and a fencer, is centuries old through the use of Lazarus Pits and thus holds several lifetime's worth of skills, resources, and contacts.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Ra's al Ghul was several centuries old before he ever encountered <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Batman">Batman</a>. Replenishing his aged, injured, or dead body with a bath in a Lazarus Pit, Ra's has survived through the centuries, all the while accumulating wealth, knowledge, and power. Ra's is a criminal and scientific genius, particularly in the field of alchemy. He also rivals Batman in hand-to-hand combat and sword fighting and was the co leader of the League of Assassins. He is constantly accompanied by a servant given the title Ubu, who is typically an especially dangerous fighter.<br /><br />When a person uses a Lazarus Pit, the person emerges temporarily insane. It has always been implied that repeated use of the Lazarus Pit could have subtle lasting effects, and no one has used as many Lazarus Pits as has Ra's. It isn't difficult to conjecture that use of the Lazarus Pits may have driven Ra's completely insane.<br /><br />Ra's's goal is a world in perfect environmental balance, a goal he will achieve at any cost. He believes that the best way to do so is to eliminate most of humanity. That he has the means to achieve his goal makes him extremely dangerous and brings him into frequent conflict with Batman. Ra's usually tries to assault the world's human populace with a biological weapon, such as a genetically-engineered virus.<br /><br />Ra's is among Batman's most formidable foes. Not only can he physically and mentally challenge "the Detective" (the name by which Ra's always refers to Batman), but he has also deduced Batman's secret identity.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/secret_files/pdfs/ras_al_ghul.pdf">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.spider-bob.com/villains/dc/RasAlGhul.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ras_Al_Ghul">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Bane|Batman|Black Canary|Superman|Wonder Woman</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="hybrid" date="1980" gender="female" morality="hero" era="Bronze" owner="DC" currently="Retired">		<name>Raven</name>      <identity>Rachel Roth</identity>      <creator>Marv Wolfman and George Perez</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>Nyctokinesis, teleportation, healing ability, psionic emotional manipulation, astral form called a Soul Self</powers>      <weakness>Emotional instability, demonic influences.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Raven has been a prominent member of The New Teen Titans, and is currently a member of the modern Teen Titans. Raven is an empath, she can teleport, and send out her Soul Self which can fight physically as well as act as Raven's eyes and ears away from her body. Her cartoon counterpart has telekinesis, which enables her to control anything by her mind.<br /><br />A dark, moody character, Raven is the half-breed daughter of a human mother named Arella and the demon overlord Trigon. She grew up in a pacifist place called Azarath, where she was taught to "control her emotions" in order to suppress and control her inherited demonic powers.<br /><br />The team was eventually able to defeat Trigon and seal him in an interdimensional prison. However, Raven still had to fight her father's influence, as he was not completely destroyed. More than once, Raven nearly lost control in various high stress situations in her adventures and barely regained control before Trigon could reassert himself.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/dc/Raven.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raven_%28comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Batman|Nightwing</allies>		<enemies></enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1941" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Golden" owner="Marvel" currently="Deceased">		<name>Red Skull</name>      <identity>Johann Schmidt</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee and Jack Kirby</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Super-Soldier formula, good fighting skills, strategic genius, political mastermind.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Red Skull is a Marvel Comics supervillain who is the principal enemy of <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Captain America">Captain America</a>.<br /><br />The Red Skull, Johann Schmidt, was a former Nazi general officer and confidante of Adolf Hitler. He has been closely affiliated with HYDRA and is an enemy of S.H.I.E.L.D., The Avengers, and the interests of the United States of America and of the free world in general. He was physically augmented by having his mind put in the body of a clone of Captain America; giving him a body that is the pinnacle of human perfection. He has been seemingly killed in the past only to return to plague the world with schemes of world domination and genocide, time and time again.<br /><br />As with many supervillains, Johann Schmidt had a traumatic childhood that warped his mind paving the way for villainy in his adult life. Schmidt's mother died in childbirth and his father blamed Johann for it and tried to murder him, only to be stopped by the attending doctor. The father later committed suicide and Johann was orphaned. He grew up on the streets struggling to survive and his hatred of humanity grew with each day. A key episode was when he fell for a local Jewish girl, but when she spurned his clumsy advances, he murdered her. With that, his depravity grew still more.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Red_Skull_%28Johann_Shmidt%29">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/marvel/RedSkull.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_Skull">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Captain America|Magneto</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>	    <character origin="human" date="1948" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Riddler</name>      <identity>Edward Nigma</identity>      <creator>Bill Finger Dick Sprang</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>Genius level intelligence, supreme problem-solver, criminal mastermind.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal, obsessive-compulsive.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The Riddler, real name Edward Nigma, is a DC Comics supervillain and an enemy of <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Batman">Batman</a>. Created by Bill Finger and Dick Sprang, he first appeared in Detective Comics #140 (1948).<br /><br />Known for his green question mark-covered costume (either as a skintight catsuit or a business suit and bowler hat), the Riddler is obsessed with riddles, puzzles, and word games. He delights in forewarning police and Batman of his capers by sending them complex riddles. Sometimes he is shown to drive a "Riddlermobile," a green car with "???" on the license plate. In the animated series, he carries a trick cane.<br /><br />Portrayals of the Riddler have become darker in recent years. Whereas he was once portrayed as a playful trickster, he is now the victim of an intense obsessive compulsion disorder. This was perhaps best shown in a 1999 issue of Gotham Adventures, in which he tried to refrain from leaving a riddle, but failed: "You don't understand... I really didn't want to leave you any clues. I really planned never to go back to Arkham Asylum. But I left you a clue anyway. So I... I have to go back there. Because I might need help. I... I might actually be crazy."<br /><br />As his riddles are in fact a bizarre obsessive compulsion, his attempts to stop himself from sending them have met with failure. He cannot simply kill his opponents when he has the upper hand, but has to put them in a deathtrap to see if he can devise a life and death intellectual challenge that the hero cannot solve and escape. However, unlike many of Batman's themed enemies, Riddler's compulsion is quite flexible, allowing him to commit any crime as long as he can describe it in a riddle or puzzle. He often has two female assistants who help him, usually named a combination of Quiz, Query or Echo.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/dc/Riddler.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Riddler">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Joker|Penguin</allies>		<enemies>Batman</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="mutant" date="1981" gender="female" morality="hero" era="Bronze" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Rogue</name>      <identity>Unknown</identity>      <creator>Chris Claremont and Michael Golden</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Involuntary absorption of powers and memories through skin-to-skin contact, flight, plasma blasts, ability to view infra-red, radiation immunity.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Rogue is a comic book superhero in the Marvel Comics universe and a member of the X-Men. She was created by Chris Claremont and Michael Golden in <em>The Avengers Annual #10</em> (August 1981).<br /><br />Rogue is a mutant with the ability to temporarily absorb the memories, thoughts, and abilities (including superhuman abilities) of others via skin-to-skin contact. This transference usually causes the victim to fall unconscious and/or become weakened, but it can kill if it is prolonged. The duration of this drain varies according to the length of time that the contact is maintained; the generally accepted ratio is 60 seconds of absorbed abilities for every 1 second of skin-to-skin contact. Prolonged contact also can result in a permanent impression of the template she absorbed.<br /><br />Early in her career, Rogue permanently absorbed the powers of Ms. Marvel, gaining superhuman strength, flight, near-invulnerability, and a "seventh sense". Most recently, she permanently absorbed a large portion of the powers of the Japanese mutant superhero Sunfire as he was dying. She now has his power to absorb solar energy and convert it into ionized plasma. She can channel her solar powers through her hands as streams of fiery thermal energy, which can burn through almost anything. She can focus her energies inward to boost her strength to superhuman levels (though not to the level she possessed when she had Ms. Marvel's powers), or project it outward to surround herself in a protective force field aura. She can fly once more, now by directing her burning aura downwards in a focused jet of flame to propel herself through the air like a missile.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Rogue">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/Rogue.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rogue_(comics)">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Gambit|Iceman|Phoenix|Professor X|Psylocke|Wolverine</allies>		<enemies>Apocalypse|Magneto|Mystique</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1963" gender="female" morality="nblurred" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Missing">		<name>Scarlet Witch</name>      <identity>Wanda Maximoff</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee and Jack Kirby</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Reality warping, probability shift.</powers>      <weakness>Powers dependant on spells, spells not entirely reliable.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The Scarlet Witch (Wanda Maximoff) is a fictional character in the Marvel Comics universe, a mutant who fluctuates between being a superheroine and supervillainess. Created by Stan Lee and Jack Kirby, she first appeared in <em>X-Men #4</em> (1963).<br /><br />The Scarlet Witch is the twin sister of Quicksilver (Pietro Maximoff); the twins are the children of <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Magneto">Magneto</a> and his late wife Magda. Magda fled from Magneto before either learned that she was pregnant. The twins were born in the fictional country of Transia on the equally-fictitious Wundagore Mountain, the prison of the Elder God Chthon. Chthon's residual energies altered Wanda, giving her the ability to use magic, in addition to her mutant power.<br /><br />Initially, the Scarlet Witch had the ability to manipulate probability via her "hexes" (often manifesting physically as "hex spheres" or "hex bolts"). These hexes are relatively short range, and are limited to her line of sight. Casting a hex requires a gesture and concentration on her part, though the gestures are largely a focus for the concentration. Early in her career, her hexes were unconscious on her part, and would be automatically triggered whenever she made a particular gesture, regardless of her intent. These hexes would only manifest "bad luck" effects. She later gained enough control over her powers that her powers only work when she wants them to, and they are not limited to negative effects.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Iron_Man_%28Anthony_Stark%29">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/ScarletWitch.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scarlet_Witch">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Magneto</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="mutant" date="1942" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Shade</name>      <identity>Richard Swift</identity>      <creator>George Brenner</creator>      <company>Comics Magazine Company (now DC Comics)</company>      <powers>Nyctokinesis, immortality.</powers>      <weakness>Feels no pain or connections to other, powers based on a link to a reservoir of darkness.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The Shade is a DC Comics character, a villain created in the 1940s who would fight against two generations of superheroes, most notably the Golden Age and Silver Age <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Flash">Flashes</a>. Initially a man with some unexplained control over the dark, his powers were revealed to be a connection to the Shadowlands, a dimension of primordial, quasi-sentient darkness which Shade, as well as other characters with similar powers, can channel for various effects.<br /><br />He would serve as a member of several ad hoc super-villain teams and played a role in the first meeting of the Golden Age and Silver Age Flashes.<br /><br />The Shade was actually Richard Swift, an English gentleman present at an undetailed mystical tragedy. He (as well as the mysterious dwarf Culp) survived the event, but was left linked to a reservoir of darkness, a man but also a monster of sorts, never aging and rarely feeling any pain or true connection to others. In Victorian London, he would make enemies of the corrupt Ludlow family, whose efforts to kill him would span 150 years (and would be recounted in a 1997 limited series). He was also an acquaintance of Oscar Wilde, who told him the "true story" behind The Picture of Dorian Gray.<br /><br />As time passed, Swift would come to call himself the Shade, and move to the frontier town of Opal City in America. He would often play the rogue - although never in Opal City itself - but just as often play the hero, befriending Opal City's sheriff, Matt Savage (once DC's Western hero, Scalphunter). All the while, he would amass a personal fortune while rejecting conventional morality.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/dc/Shade.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Shade">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Vandal Savage</allies>		<enemies>Flash</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1961" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Silver" owner="DC" currently="Jailed">		<name>Shadow-Thief</name>      <identity>Carl Sands</identity>      <creator>Gardner Fox and Joe Kubert</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>Nyctokinesis, immortality.</powers>      <weakness>Delusion, powers derived from a special suit.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Shadow-Thief is a DC Comics supervillain and a recurring foe to <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Hawkman">Hawkman</a>. He was created by Gardner Fox and Joe Kubert, and first appeared in <em>The Brave and the Bold #36</em> (July 1961).<br /><br />While growing up in Japan, Carl Sands learned ninjitsu techniques and became a rather undistinguished industrial saboteur, accepting unremarkable sums to hinder and eliminate his clients' rivals. Thanagarian criminal Byth, then, hired Sands to steal Hawkman and Hawkwoman's ship. To help Sands with this job, Byth gave him a Thanagarian belt device/"shadow vest" known as a Dimensionmeter, which gave Sands the ability to shift his body into a shadow form.<br /><br />Hawkman eventually defeated him, but Shadow-Thief would come into conflict with him many times after that. He would later become a member of the Injustice Gang which came into conflict with Hawkman and his allies, the Justice League of America. He lost the belt to the Phantom Stranger, but he gained a shadow suit. He eventually sold his soul to Neron for more power. Neron gave him a more powerful shadow suit with the ability to turn other people and objects into shadows.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/dc/ShadowThief.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shadow-Thief">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Joker|Lex Luthor|Ocean Master</allies>		<enemies>Hawkman</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="alien" date="1966" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Silver Surfer</name>      <identity>Norrin Radd</identity>      <creator>Jack Kirby and Stan Lee</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Wields the Power Cosmic, giving him control over the four fundamental forces of the universe thus giving him a vast array of superhuman abilities.</powers>      <weakness>No blatant weaknesses.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The Silver Surfer is a Marvel Comics superhero. Created by Jack Kirby and Stan Lee, he first appeared in <em>The Fantastic Four #48</em> (1966).<br /><br />The Surfer was originally Norrin Radd, a young astronomer of the planet Zenn-La. He agreed to serve as a herald for the alien <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Galactus">Galactus</a> to save Zenn-La from the planet-consuming super being. Galactus granted Norrin Radd enormous cosmic powers, a silvery appearance and a surfboard-like vehicle, all of which modeled after a childhood fantasy of Radd's. Thereafter, he roamed the cosmos, searching for new planets for Galactus to consume until, after an encounter with Earth's Fantastic Four, he betrayed Galactus, who doomed the Surfer to exile on Earth.<br /><br />In the very earliest stories, Kirby envisioned the Surfer as a semi-divine being created by the godlike Galactus, immeasurably powerful yet lacking the most basic understanding of good or evil. Clearly drawing inspiration from Rousseau, Lee's script allowed this completely amoral entity to develop a sense of compassion through contact with the gentle Alicia Masters, a blind sculptress somehow capable of perceiving the surfer's innate nobility.<br /><br />The Silver Surfer possesses vast power known as the "Power Cosmic," gained when Galactus restructured his former body. He has the ability to channel ambient cosmic energy into his body at will, and expel it violently as concussive force or gently as a means to restructure molecules according to his mental design. He can generate beams of energy with sufficient destructive force to annihilate a planet or generate such subtle amounts of energy to restructure the molecules of the natural pigments within a plant to change its color.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Silver_Surfer">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/SilverSurfer.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Silver_Surfer">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Invisible Woman</allies>		<enemies>Doctor Doom|Galactus|Thanos</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="demon" date="1994" gender="male" morality="antihero" era="Bronze" owner="Image" currently="Active">		<name>Spawn</name>      <identity>Al Simmons</identity>      <creator>Todd McFarlane</creator>      <company>Image Comics</company>      <powers>Super strength, super endurance, super speed, flight, shape-shifting, teleportation, immortality, vast magical powers, living symbiotic costume.</powers>      <weakness>Unable to die outside of a patch of alley known as "The Deadzone" unless beheaded by a weapon of heaven.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Spawn is the main character of a comic book of the same title from Todd McFarlane Productions. Spawn was one of the flagship titles at the launch of Image Comics, and the first issue hit the newstands in May of 1992.<br /><br />Al Simmons was a highly decorated member of the Secret Service (notably saving the President in an attempted assassination) and the CIA. After being murdered in a foreign country by his superior Jason Wynn, Simmons is sent to hell because of his life as a mercenary. Making a deal with the devil, Simmons agrees to become a Hellspawn and serve Malebolgia if he is allowed to see his wife, Wanda, one last time. Malebolgia returns Simmons to the living realm, but with only the barest of memory, a badly burned body, and a watch dog, the Clown. Simmons is unaware that five years have passed. His wife has married his best friend, Terry Fitzgerald, and the two have a daughter, Cyan.<br /><br />His life over, Simmons has two choices before him: follow Malebolgia, or renounce the devil. The two choices come in the form of Clown, a diminutive, portly, disgusting minor demon (who can transform into the huge, fanged, clawed <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Violator">Violator</a>), and Cogliostro (Cog), an apparently homeless old man who knows more about Simmons (whom both call Spawn) and his situation than even he knows.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/indi/Spawn.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spawn_%28comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Violator</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="alien" date="1940" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Spectre</name>      <identity>Aztar</identity>      <creator>Jerry Siegel and Bernard Baily</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>Divine mystical enhancements granting near omnipotent abilities.</powers>      <weakness>No blatant weaknesses.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The Spectre is a fictional cosmic entity and superhero who has appeared in numerous comic books published by DC Comics. The character first appeared in <em>More Fun Comics #52</em> (February 1940), and was created by Jerry Siegel and Bernard Baily.<br /><br />The Spectre's career began in the late 1930s, when hard-boiled police detective Jim Corrigan was murdered. His spirit refused to pass into the afterlife, however, and, in the guise of a chalk-white man in a green cloak, it sought bloody vengeance against Corrigan's murderers in a grim, supernatural fashion.<br /><br />During the mid-1940s, the popularity of superhero comics began to decline, and the Spectre suffered as a result. He was reduced to playing the role of "guardian angel" to a bumbling character called "Percival Popp, the Super Cop." The character had formerly been part of the Justice Society of America featured in All-Star Comics, but he was replaced in 1944.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/secret_files/pdfs/the_spectre.pdf">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.spider-bob.com/heroes/dc/SpectreI.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spectre_(comics)">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies></enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="altered" date="1962" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Spider-Man</name>      <identity>Peter Benjamin Parker</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee and Steve Ditko</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Ability to stick to solid surfaces, super-strength, precognitive "spider-sense", enhanced speed, reflexes and agility, both synthesized and organic ability to produce spider-web, paralyzing poisonous stingers located in arms, ability to see in the dark, and the ability to "feel" his environment.</powers>      <weakness>Disruption of "spider-sense".</weakness>	  <copy><p>Spider-Man (Peter Benjamin Parker), is a Marvel Comics superhero created by writer Stan Lee and artist Steve Ditko. He first appeared in <em>Amazing Fantasy #15</em> (August 1962). He has become one of the world's most popular, enduring and well-recognized superheroes.<br /><br />Spider-Man expanded the dramatic potential of the fantasy and superhero subgenres. Lee's early Spider-Man stories broke new ground by attempting to relate to readers with a younger character who balanced his personal struggles with his heroic exploits. Since his inception, Spider-Man has encouraged many comic books to expand the personae of new or previously existing characters.<br /><br />Since his debut, Peter Parker has grown from a shy high school student to a troubled college undergrad and graduate student to a married man and a professional. These and several other changes have provoked arguments as to whether or not the core concepts of the character are still intact.<br /><br />When he was 15 years and 7 months old, Parker attended a science exhibition where he was bitten by a spider which had been irradiated. The spider bite gave Parker an array of spider-like powers. In addition to his physical powers, Peter Parker successfully designed and utilized mechanical "web-shooters" to spin webs in a variety of ways. In the current Spider-Man stories, he produces his webs from organic spinnerets in his wrists and no longer requires the mechanical web shooters, most likely to bring character recognition inline with fans who mainly know him from his movie incarnation. This change has proven to be very controversial among fans.<br /><br />Spider-Man has one of the best-known rogues galleries in comics. His most famous enemies include the <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Green Goblin">Green Goblin</a>, <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Doctor Octopus">Doctor Octopus</a>, and <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Venom">Venom</a>. Like Spider-Man himself, a large percentage of these villains have their origins based in storylines featuring scientific accidents or the misuse of scientific technology, many with animal themes.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Spider-Man_%28Peter_Parker%29">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/SpiderManI.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spiderman">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Captain America|Daredevil|Elektra|Hulk|Invisible Woman|Iron Man|Thor|Wolverine</allies>		<enemies>Carnage|Doctor Doom|Green Goblin|Juggernaut|Kingpin|Punisher|Venom</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="alien" date="1958" gender="female" morality="hero" era="Silver" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Supergirl</name>      <identity>Kara Zor-El</identity>      <creator>Otto Binder and Al Plastino</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>Above-average agility and dexterity, expertise in cat burglar training, steel spring-loaded climbing pitons and razor-sharp retractable nails allow her to scale vertical surfaces, wields an assortment of bullwhips and cat-o'-nine tails as gymnastic equipment.</powers>      <weakness>Kryptonite, magic, mnetal manipulation.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Supergirl is a DC Comics superhero, generally considered the female counterpart to <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Superman">Superman</a>. She was created by writer Otto Binder and artist Al Plastino. Binder also created female counterparts for Captain Marvel (Mary Marvel) and <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Captain America">Captain America</a> (Miss America).<br /><br />The character of Supergirl was introduced in <em>Action Comics #252</em> (May 1959) as Kara Zor-El, the last survivor of Argo City of the planet Krypton, which had survived the explosion of the planet and had drifted through space. When the inhabitants of the colony were slain by Kryptonite, Kara was sent to Earth by her father Zor-El to be raised by her cousin Kal-El, known as Superman. Fearing that she might not be recognized by Superman, Kara's parents provided a costume based closely on the Man of Steel's own. This uniform served as her crime-fighting attire for the first decade of her adventures in print.<br /><br />Upon meeting Kara - who on Earth now had superpowers identical to her cousin's - Superman decided she would become his secret weapon, and explained that her presence on Earth must be kept confidential while he trained Kara in the use of her new powers. Kara adopted the identity of Linda Lee, an orphan at Midvale Orphanage, hiding her short blonde locks beneath a brunette wig. Her adventures often accompanied the main Superman story in issues of Action Comics. They typically revolved around secretly helping fellow orphans, although occasionally she was allowed to play a small role alongside her famous cousin. She also became a member of the Legion of Super-Heroes alongside Superboy, the teenage incarnation of her cousin.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/secret_files/pdfs/supergirl.pdf">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/dc/SupergirlV.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Supergirl">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Batman|Superman|Wonder Woman</allies>		<enemies>Darkseid|Lex Luthor</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>		    <character origin="alien" date="1938" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Retired">		<name>Superman</name>      <identity>Clark Kent</identity>      <creator>Joe Shuster and Jerry Siegel</creator>      <company>National Comics (now DC Comics)</company>      <powers>Vast super strength, speed, and stamina, multiple extra sensory and vision powers, invulnerability, longevity, flight.</powers>      <weakness>Kryptonite, magic.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Superman is a fictional character and superhero of DC Comics who first appeared in <em>Action Comics #1</em> in 1938 and is considered the first character to embody the particular combination of traits that characterize the modern superhero.<br /><br />The character, created by Joe Shuster and Jerry Siegel for National Comics (today DC Comics), subsequently appeared in various radio serials, television programs, films, and video games.<br /><br />Superman was born Kal-El on the planet Krypton and, as an infant, was rocketed to Earth by Jor-El, his scientist father, moments before Krypton exploded. When not fighting the forces of evil as Superman, he lives among humanity as Clark Kent, a "mild-mannered reporter" for the Daily Planet.<br /><br />Originally, Superman's personality could be rough and destructive. Although nowhere near as cold-blooded as the early <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Batman">Batman</a>, the early Superman did not have a "no-kill" policy and evildoers would occasionally meet fatal ends when dealing with the hero. Recent writers have attempted to deepen Superman's persona and provide a rationale for his goodness. Far from a perfect individual, Superman is often pictured with a sense of unbounded idealism mixed with restraint provided by his sense of fairness and compassion for others. He is also a man with an incredible depth of feeling, often struggling with the differences between the right answer and the practical one. In many ways, Superman is truly one of the most "human" heroes conceived, since he responds to emotional grief in stark contrast to the way he shrugs off bullets, bombs, and death-rays.<br /><br />Lois Lane is perhaps the character most commonly associated with Superman, as his colleague, love interest, and later confidante of his dual identities, and now wife to Clark Kent. Incarnations of Supergirl, Krypto the Superdog, and Superboy have also been major characters in the mythos, as well as Batman and the Justice League of America.<br /><br />Superman also has a rogues gallery of supervillain enemies, including his most well-known enemy, <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Lex Luthor">Lex Luthor</a>. The alien android known as <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Brainiac">Brainiac</a> is considered by some as the second worst nemesis of Superman. Other enemies of note include the fifth-dimensional imp <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Mister Mxyzptlk">Mister Mxyzptlk</a>, the imperfect Superman clone Bizarro, criminal cyborg Metallo, the raging monster <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Doomsday">Doomsday</a>, and one of the most powerful beings in the DC universe, <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Darkseid">Darkseid</a>.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/features/superman/">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/dc/Superman.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Superman">Wikipedia</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.sequart.com/superman.htm">The Continuity Pages</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Aquaman|Batman|Black Canary|Flash|Green Arrow|Green Lantern|Hawkman|Martian Manhunter|Plastic Man|Supergirl|Wonder Woman</allies>		<enemies>Brainiac|Darkseid|Doomsday|Lex Luthor|Mister Mxyzptlk|Ra's al Ghul|Vandal Savage</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="mutant" date="1973" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Thanos</name>      <identity>Thanos</identity>      <creator>Jim Starlin</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Energy manipulation, vast superhuman strength, stamina, and durability, superhuman level intellect, immortal.</powers>      <weakness>Love of Death, overconfidence.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Thanos is a fictional character created by Jim Starlin and published by Marvel Comics. He is a Titanian Eternal and is often referred to as The Mad Titan.<br /><br />The name "Thanos" is from the root of the Greek word for "death", thanatos. In the modern Greek language, Thanos is a nickname of those with the proper name Athanasius. He was originally conceived as a Marvel Comics version of Jack Kirby's <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Darkseid">Darkseid</a>.<br /><br />Thanos was born on Saturn's moon, Titan. He is a mutant of the race of Eternals that live in a colony of that moon. He is a son of the colony's ruler, Mentor, and brother to Eros.<br /><br />For unknown reasons, he was born with purple-grey, hide-like skin and a massive body. Although treated fairly by his people, Thanos grew distant and obsessive. By means of bionic implants and long hours of strength and ability-augmenting meditation, Thanos became the most powerful of the Eternals. As his powers grew, so too did his ambition. He was eventually exiled from Titan for hideous crimes, including matricide.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Thanos">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/marvel/Thanos.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thanos">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Captain America|Captain Marvel|Galactus|Hulk|Iron Man|Silver Surfer|Thor</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1936" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Deceased">		<name>The Clock</name>      <identity>Brian O'Brien</identity>      <creator>George Brenner</creator>      <company>Comics Magazine Company</company>      <powers>None.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The Clock is a fictional masked crime-fighter published during the Golden Age of Comic Books. According to the <em>Overstreet Comic Book Price Guide</em>, The Clock was the first masked hero to appear in American comic books.<br /><br />The character's initial appearances were two-page features that left little space for character development, but the Clock's secret identity was eventually revealed to be society man and former district attorney Brian O'Brien, whose background in college sports helped prepare him for heroism. As the Clock, he wore a three-piece suit, a fedora, and a black full-face mask (which was replaced by a domino mask years later). He usually left a calling card that bore an image of a clock and the words "The Clock Has Struck."<br /><br />It is believed that Quality editor Will Eisner was in part inspired by The Clock to create <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,The Spirit">The Spirit</a>.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://members.tripod.com/srca1941/AAC34-2-1.html">All-Amazing Comics #34</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Clock">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Doctor Doom|Invisible Woman</allies>		<enemies></enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1932" gender="male" morality="antihero" era="Platinum" owner="DC" currently="Retired">		<name>The Shadow</name>      <identity>Giovanni "John" Zatara</identity>      <creator>Walter Gibson</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>None.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The Shadow is a fictional character created by Walter Gibson.<br /><br />Initially a pulp hero, The Shadow became even more famous on radio, and has since been featured also in comic books, television, and at least seven motion pictures. Even after decades, the unmistakable introduction from The Shadow has earned a place in the American lexicon: "Who knows what evil lurks in the hearts of men? The Shadow knows!"<br /><br />Some argue that The Shadow birthed much of the concept we have come to know as the modern superhero; such characters as <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Batman">Batman</a> and The Green Hornet reference Lamont Cranston's alter ego. Both characters operated mostly by night, and the Green Hornet in particular operated outside the law, insinuating himself into criminal plots in order to put an end to the activities of master criminals. But whereas the Shadow carried a real gun, the Green Hornet carried only a lightweight pistol that fired non-lethal gas and, later a retractable electronic laser "sting" used mostly to cut through thick barriers. While Batman briefly carried a pistol in his first few years, he quickly abandoned the use of weapons altogether; his creators are said to have feared that giving the character a sidearm would make him resemble the Shadow too greatly.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://thepulp.net/theshadow.html">ThePulp.Net</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/indi/Shadow.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Shadow">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies></enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1940" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Missing">		<name>The Spirit</name>      <identity>Denny Colt</identity>      <creator>Will Eisner</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>None. Smart, tenacious and a capable fighter.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The Spirit (real name Denny Colt) is a fictional masked crime-fighter, created by Will Eisner in 1940, who starred in a Sunday-newspaper comic-book insert. His namesake, seven-page weekly series is considered one of the comic-art medium's most significant and classic works, with writer-artist Eisner creating or popularizing many of the styles, techniques, and storytelling conventions used by comics professionals decades later.<br /><br />The Spirit chronicled the adventures of an anonymous vigilante who fought crime with the blessing of the city's police commissioner, an old friend. The stories ranged through a wide variety of styles, from straightforward crime drama to lighthearted adventure, from mystery and horror to comedy and love stories, often with hybrid elements that twisted genre and expectations.<br /><br />The Spirit, referred to in one newspaper article cited below as "the only real middle-class crimefighter", was the hero persona of young detective Denny Colt. Presumed killed in the first three pages of the premiere story, Colt later revealed to his friend, Central City Police Commissioner Dolan, that he had in fact gone into suspended animation caused by one of archvillain Dr. Cobra's experiments. When Colt awakened in Wildwood Cemetery, he established a base there and, using his newfound anonymity, began a life of fighting crime wearing only a small domino mask, blue business suit, fedora hat and gloves for a costume. The Spirit dispensed justice, funding his adventures with the rewards for capturing villains.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/indi/Spirit.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Spirit">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies></enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="altered" date="1961" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Thing</name>      <identity>Reed Richards</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee and Jack Kirby</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Superhuman intelligence, durability, extreme malleability.</powers>      <weakness>Energy weapons, taffy-pullers, magic, temporary power loss.</weakness>	  <copy><p>The Thing (Benjamin Jacob "Ben" Grimm) is a fictional character in the Marvel Comics universe, a founding member of the superhero team The Fantastic Four. He was created by Jack Kirby and Stan Lee in <em>The Fantastic Four #1</em> (Nov. 1961). His trademark battle cry, "It's clobberin' time!" is one of comics' most recognizable catchphrases.<br /><br />During this unauthorized ride into the upper atmosphere of Earth, they were pelted by a cosmic ray storm and exposed to radiation against which the ship's shields were no protection. Upon crashing down to Earth each of the four learned that they had developed fantastic superpowers. Grimm had been transformed initially into a lumpy orange thing, and later evolved gradually into his more familiar massive orange humanoid form of slightly jagged earthy rock. <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Mister Fantastic">Richards</a> proposed the quartet band together to use their new abilities for the betterment of humanity, and Grimm, in a moment of understandable self-pity, adopted the superheroic sobriquet The Thing.<br /><br />Trapped in his monstrous form, Grimm was an unhappy yet reliable member of the team. He trusted in his friend Reed Richards to one day develop a cure for his condition. However, when he encountered blind sculptress Alicia Masters, Grimm developed a subconscious resistance to being transformed back to his human form. Fearing that Masters preferred him to remain in the monstrous form of the Thing, Grimm's body rejected various attempts by Richards to restore his human form lest he lose the love of Masters. His subconscious fear kept him in his rocky form and Grimm remained a stalwart member of the Fantastic Four for years.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Thing">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/ThingII.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thing_(comics)">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Captain America|Human Torch|Invisible Woman|Mister Fantastic|Spider-Man|Thor|Wolverine</allies>		<enemies>Doctor Doom|Galactus</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1962" gender="male" morality="hero" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Deceased">		<name>Thor</name>      <identity>Thor Odinson</identity>      <creator>Stan Lee, Jack Kirby, and Larry Lieber</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Enormous superhuman strength, speed and stamina, near-invulnerability , extraordinarily long life span, flight (via Mjolnir), atmokinesis, Force Blasts</powers>      <weakness>Weakened powers without Mjolnir.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Thor is the Norse god of Thunder, Lightning and Agriculture. As such, he controls storms, particularly rain and accompanying wind and thunder, as well as base elements. Thor also possesses enormous stamina, durability, speed, and is immune to all terrestrial diseases due to his god-like physical constitution. In addition, he is a superb hand-to-hand combatant, as well as one of the strongest beings in the Marvel Universe. This has been shown on various occasions, when fighting some of the most physically powerful characters (E.g. Hercules, Mangog, <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Thanos">Thanos</a>, Gladiator and the <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Hulk">Incredible Hulk</a>). Thor is also very cunning and intuitive in battle.<br /><br />The character Thor in the Marvel universe follows the traditional Norse myth to a point. The Marvel version has been seen in flashbacks as a child and teen godling who, in his early adulthood, became arrogant and self-righteous. Odin, determining his son needed to be taught humility, placed Thor, without memories of godhood, into the body and memories of an existing, partially disabled human medical student, Donald Blake.<br /><br />In battle, Thor is a legendary braggart, which has long been accepted as a natural part of the character's charm. He will often use this as both a means of sustaining morale and to convince a lesser foe to yield, usually by adding commentary to a display of power. Outside of battle, he is an honorable, loyal, and courteous individual, in Asgard considered second only to Odin in terms of nobility. He is, however, rather short-tempered.<br /><br />Thor battles enemies such as his adoptive brother Loki, who has sworn to kill him. To that end, Loki created powerful minions like the Absorbing Man and the Wrecker and manipulated other enemies like Ulik of the Trolls to challenge the thunder god; one of these manipulations resulted in the formation of the superhero team called The Avengers, a team in which for years Thor has served as one of the core members.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Thor_%28Thor_Odinson%29">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/Thor.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thor_%28Marvel_Comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Captain America|Invisible Woman|Iron Man|Spider-Man|Wolverine</allies>		<enemies>Hulk|Thanos</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="altered" date="1943" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Golden" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Vandal Savage</name>      <identity>Vandar Adg</identity>      <creator>Alfred Bester Martin Nodell</creator>      <company>National Comics (now DC Comics)</company>      <powers>Immortality, above average strength, speed, stamina, agility and senses, excellent combat skills, schooled in millennia of history, warfare and science.</powers>      <weakness>Emotional attachments.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Vandal Savage is a fictional character and supervillain in the DC Comics universe. Savage first appeared in <em><a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Green Lantern">Green Lantern</a> (volume 1) # 10</em> in 1943, and was created by Alfred Bester and Martin Nodell.<br /><br />Savage's threat lies in the fact that he is a brilliant tactician, an immortal and his technological prowess. He is one of DC's most persistent villains and has fought many different heroes throughout history.<br /><br />In the days of prehistory, 50,000 BC, Savage was known as a caveman named Vandar Adg, leader of the Blood Tribe, who would find himself bathed in the radiation of a mysterious meteorite, which gave him incredible intellect and immortality. An observer from the Bear Tribe would later approach that same meteorite and become Savage's eternal nemesis, the Immortal Man, possessing the power to resurrect as a new persona every time he is killed.<br /><br />Having lived so long, Savage has butted heads with possibly every single hero featured in the DC Universe, past, present, and future, most notably the Justice Society of America and the Justice League of America. At present, in DC universe, Savage is about 52,000 years old.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/dc/VandalSavage.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vandal_Savage">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Shade</allies>		<enemies>Flash|Green Lantern|Hawkman|Superman</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="alien" date="1988" gender="male" morality="antihero" era="Bronze" owner="DC" currently="Missing">		<name>Venom</name>      <identity>Eddie Brock</identity>      <creator>David Michelinie and Todd McFarlane</creator>      <company>DC Comics</company>      <powers>A human host linked to an alien symbiote whose previous link with Spider-Man created the equivalents of his abilities, webbing, shape-shifting, cannot be detected by Spider-Man's spider-sense.</powers>      <weakness>Heat, high frequency sounds.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Venom (Eddie Brock) is a comic book anti-hero in the Marvel Comics universe, and an enemy of <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Spider-Man">Spider-Man</a>. He is usually counted as one of the web-slinger's greatest enemies, alongside <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Doctor Octopus">Doctor Octopus</a> and the <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Green Goblin">Green Goblin</a>.<br /><br />Venom is jet black with a large symbol of a white black widow spider on his chest. He has a gaping mouth filled with razor-sharp teeth, a long, lolling tongue, and is often depicted drooling a green slime-like substance. He is stronger than Spider-Man and his webbing, which the symbiote generates from the mass of its own body, is more durable than Spider-Man's mechanically-generated webs. The symbiote's shapeshifting ability allows Venom to camouflage himself like a chameleon or to assume the likeness of nearly any person. Venom also has the ability to remain undetected by Spider-Man's spider-sense, making him one of Spider-Man's deadliest foes. However, the symbiote is highly vulnerable to fire and high-frequency sound.<br /><br />Despite his lethal ability and homicidal hatred of Spider-Man, Venom remains curiously protective of those he considers "innocent". He will generally avoid killing bystanders or innocents in his quest for vengeance. Of course, the fact that he is insane means that his definitions of "innocent" and "necessary casualties" fluctuate as his needs demand. He has teamed up with Spider-Man on several occasions, most notably to battle the symbiote's homicidal offspring, <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Carnage">Carnage</a>, and has occasionally worked alongside other anti-heroes and superheroes, such as the <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Punisher">Punisher</a> and <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Ghost Rider">Ghost Rider</a>. His concept of justice is simply to kill criminals brutally and without hesitation, even for crimes as small as theft, which has made him greatly feared. He can even be harsh to the heroes he works with, but he later forgets his disagreements with them and focuses on beating the opponent.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Venom_%28Eddie_Brock%29">Marvel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/villains/marvel/VenomI.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Venom_%28comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Carnage|Spider-Ma|Wolverine</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="demon" date="1994" gender="male" morality="villain" era="Bronze" owner="Image" currently="Active">		<name>Violator</name>      <identity>Unknown</identity>      <creator>Todd McFarlane</creator>      <company>Image Comics</company>      <powers>Telepathy, superhuman strength and resilience, shape-shifting.</powers>      <weakness>Mortal.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Violator is the true form of the Clown, an antagonist in Todd McFarlane's <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.XMLink,Spawn">Spawn</a> comic series.<br /><br />His purpose is to guide Hellspawn towards fulfilling Malebolgia's desire: to cultivate evil souls on Earth for Hell's army. But because of jealousy and his own ego, the Violator is doomed to fail; this is his own particular torment.<br /><br />He claims to have been born from the magic of Dr. John Dee in the 16th century, and yet he has dealt with a Hellspawn in the Middle Ages, four hundred years earlier. His true origin is lost in the mists of time and the fumes of Hell. He brags that he could destroy a Hellspawn to its very face, and then whines when the battle turns against him. His fighting is vicious, but not strong enough to overcome his master's pets. The Violator is a contradiction both in form and substance.<br /><br />His methods are base, mean and cruel. He has yet to come close to his master's expectations, always foiling the best laid plans. But he has to prove himself to the Malebolgia that he is better than mere humans, a better choice to be a Hellspawn. One day, he has told himself for centuries, he'll get up the courage to tell "the boss" what he feels.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Violator_(comics)">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies></allies>		<enemies>Spawn</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="mutant" date="1974" gender="male" morality="antihero" era="Silver" owner="Marvel" currently="Active">		<name>Wolverine</name>      <identity>Logan, born James Howlett</identity>      <creator>Len Wein, John Romita Sr., and Herb Trimpe</creator>      <company>Marvel Comics</company>      <powers>Regenerative healing factor, retarded aging, retractable claws, Adamantium-laced skeleton and claws, superhumanly acute senses, heightened strength, stamina, agility and reaction time.</powers>      <weakness>Massive organ damage, blood loss, magnetic fields.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Wolverine (born James Howlett, aka Logan) is a Marvel Comics superhero and member of the X-Men. Wolverine was created by Len Wein and John Romita Sr. with some additional influence by Herb Trimpe.<br /><br />As a mutant, Wolverine has an enhanced healing factor which allows him the ability to heal virtually any wound at an alarming rapid rate. He also possesses keen animal-like senses and reflexes and has three (foot long) claws that protrude from the backs of his hands. The claws and his entire skeleton are laced with the unbreakable metal alloy adamantium. He is an unparalleled master of combat who will not hesitate to meet lethal force in kind. Wolverine's fierce nature helped forge the mold for comic book anti-heroes. His willingness to use deadly force, his efforts to come to terms with his questionable past and his angst-filled inner conflicts have become standard for anti-heroes.<br /><br />Though seemingly brutish, Wolverine is actually highly intelligent. Due to his increased lifespan, he has been able to travel around the world and amass an intimate knowledge of many foreign languages, customs and cultures. During his years in Japan, he became a master of martial arts both armed and unarmed: he is especially skilled in the use of the katana. He can use most weapons, traditional or modern, long or close range. He is also an accomplished pilot and is extremely well trained in espionage and covert/black operations. Wolverine speaks fluent English, Japanese, Russian, Chinese, Cheyenne, Spanish, and Lakota, and has some working knowledge of Vietnamese, Thai, German and French.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.marvel.com/universe/Wolverine_%28James_Howlett%29">Mavel Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/marvel/Wolverine.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wolverine_%28comics%29">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Captain America|Gambit|Iceman|Iron Man|Professor X|Psylocke|Spider-Man|Thor</allies>		<enemies>Apocalypse|Galactus|Juggernaut|Hulk|Magneto|Mystique|Punisher</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>			<character origin="human" date="1941" gender="female" morality="hero" era="Golden" owner="DC" currently="Active">		<name>Wonder Woman</name>      <identity>Diana</identity>      <creator>William Moulton Marston and Elizabeth (Sadie) Holloway Marston</creator>      <company>All-American Publications (now DC Comics)</company>      <powers>Flight, super-strength, super-speed, highly developed fighting skills, enhanced hearing, enhanced vision, animal empathy, regeneration, sisterhood with fire, high resistance to magic.</powers>      <weakness>Becames a normal mortal woman when her Amazonian bracelets are bound together by a man, enters a "berserker rage" if her bracelets are removed.</weakness>	  <copy><p>Wonder Woman is a DC Comics superhero. Co-created by William Moulton Marston with his wife Elizabeth (Sadie) Holloway Marston, Wonder Woman first appeared in <em>All Star Comics #8</em> (Dec. 1941). She is one of the first female superheroes and arguably the most famous.<br /><br />In most adaptations, Wonder Woman is Princess Diana of the Amazon warrior tribe of Greek mythology. "Diana" is the Roman name for the Greek goddess on whom this character is based; "Artemis" is her Greek name. The Amazon ambassador to the larger world, she possesses several superhuman abilities and gifts from the Greek gods including the Lasso of Truth created from the Golden Girdle of Gaea and indestructable silver bracelets formed from the shield Aegis. For several years she was described, in the splash page of each story, as being "beautiful as Aphrodite, wise as Athena, swifter than Mercury and stronger than Hercules." She is also a member of the Justice League.<br /><br />Marston designed Wonder Woman as a distinctly feminist character and many subsequent writers, especially those of the 1970s and afterward, have written her as such. From her inception, Wonder Woman was not out to just stop criminals, but to reform them. On a small island off Paradise Island was Transformation Island, a rehabilitation complex created by the Amazons to house and reform criminals. A large concept in his concept of Wonder Woman was one of "loving submission", in which one would be kind to others and be willing to surrender to them out of agape. This has often been parodied as male criminals being so enamored with her beauty that they surrender to enjoy her company however briefly in some fashion.<br /><br />During this same early period, Wonder Woman joined the Justice Society of America as its first female member. The Justice Society was the first super-team, featured in All Star Comics, and times being what they were, Wonder Woman, despite being one of the most powerful members, was the group's secretary.</p></copy>	  <external><p><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://www.dccomics.com/secret_files/pdfs/wonder_woman.pdf">DC Comics</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://spider-bob.com/heroes/dc/WonderWomanI.htm">Spider-Bob's</a><br /><a href="asfunction:exURL,http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wonder_woman">Wikipedia</a></p></external>	  <arcs>	  	<allies>Aquaman|Batman|Black Canary|Flash|Green Arrow|Green Lantern|Hawkman|Martian Manhunter|Plastic Man|Superman</allies>		<enemies>Darkseid|Ra's al Ghul</enemies>	  </arcs>    </character>  </database>