<?xml version="1.0"?>    <about><p>So it has come to this has it? You have no clue what is going on do you? I have failed you as a designer and you have failed me as a visitor. Well, hopefully I can help you out a little bit. This whole site deals with super-heroes, super-villains, and all sorts of super-people. If you are looking for something else, I can't help you. For the rest of you, all the poop and pretty pictures are located in that circle to the left. Here's the breakdown:<br /><br /><strong>Center</strong><br />Smack dab in the middle you will find nifty drawings of whichever character you are focused on. <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.tutorial,center">Show me!</a><br /><br /><strong>Filter Ring</strong><br />Each of the words in this ring represent a mode of organizing all the characters. Clicking on DATE will sort all the characters according to when they were first created. GENDER will sort by if the character is male of female. And so on. And so forth. <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.tutorial,filter">Prove it!</a><br /><br /><strong>Legend Ring</strong><br />After selecting on of the filters in the previous ring, and the characters are sorted, this ring will let you know what different categories are. Such as in GENDER, blue colored characters are MALE and pink colored characters are FEMALE. <a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.tutorial,key">Let me see this!</a><br /><br /><strong>Character Ring</strong><br />This is the outermost ring, and consists of a box and the name of a character. Clicking on the name will fill the center circle with an image of that character and bring up all sorts of swell text for reading or ignoring right here. If a name is red, that means you are looking at the info for that fellow. If it is orange, that means that dude has some relationship to whomever you are focusing on at the moment.<a href="asfunction:_parent._parent.tutorial,names">What?</a><br /><br /><strong>Searching</strong><br />The search box will sift through all the characters based the words you type here, such as "Batman" or "super rad" and let you know what characters related to whatever it happens to be you are so interested in.<br /><br /><strong>Intro</strong><br />Clicking this will return you to the first screen you saw upon coming to this awesome encyclopedia.<br /><br /><strong>About</strong><br />This is supply you with all sorts of boring copyright information, bibliography, and the poop on me, the guy that built all this for you.<br /><br /><strong>Help</strong><br />This!<br /><br /><strong>Report</strong><br />After checking out five characters, the report is added to the menu. The report analyzes what you have been looking at and recommends some other characters you may not know about.<br /><br /><strong>History</strong><br />A running log of every character you have looked at and which filter you were sorting by at the time.</p></about>	